-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品   分享创作之乐，共赏字幕之美
-=PLX&TLF字幕组=-
翻译:糸色董董 Fatreo   校对:糸色董董 tpring V&S:Vience psjmz
巴黎 1905
歌剧院舞台
Sold! Your number, sir?
成交，先生，请告诉我您的号码
Thank you.
谢谢
Lot 663, then. Ladies and gentlemen,
女士们先生们，接下来是第663号拍卖品
曾在本剧院上演过的夏拉莫的歌剧《汉尼拔》的海报
a poster for this house's production  of Hannibal by Chalumeau.
Showing here.
请看
Do I have 10 francs?
十法郎起价如何？
Five, then? Five I am bid.
那就五法郎起价  有人出五法郎吗？
Six? Six. Do I see seven? Seven.
六法郎，六法郎，有人出七法郎吗？七法郎
Against you, sir, seven. Eight? Eight.
有人加到七法郎，先生
Eight once.
八法郎，八法郎，八法郎一次
Selling twice.
八法郎两次
Sold, to Raoul, Vicomte de Chagny.
成交，由拉乌尔，夏尼伯爵得标
Thank you very much.
谢谢各位
Lot 664. Ladies and gentlemen,
女士们先生们，接下来是第664件拍卖品
a wooden pistol and three human skulls
木制手枪和三个颅骨
from the 1831 production of  Robert le Diable by Meyerbeer.
是1831年梅耶贝尔的歌剧《恶魔罗勃》的道具
Ten francs for this.
十法郎起价
Ten, thank you.
有人出十法郎，谢谢
Ten I am bid.
现在出价十法郎
Ten francs still.
仍然是十法郎
Fifteen, thank you, sir.
有人出十五法郎，谢谢
Fifteen I am bid.
现在出价十五法郎
Going for 15.
十五法郎成交
Your number, sir? Thank you.
先生，您的号码？谢谢
Lot 665. Ladies and gentlemen,
接下来，第665件拍卖品  女士们先生们
a papier-mâché musical box  in the shape of a barrel organ.
一个硬纸制的手摇式音乐盒
Attached, the figure of a monkey  in Persian robes, playing the cymbals.
上面有一只穿着波斯长袍敲钹的猴子
This item, discovered in the vaults  of the theatre,
这件拍卖品在本剧院的地窖里被找到
still in working order, ladies and gentlemen.
仍然完好无损，各位女士各位先生
Showing here.
请看实物
May I commence at 20 francs?
起价为二十法郎
Oh, come, come, ladies and gentlemen.  Fifteen, then?
女士们先生们，十五法郎呢？
Fifteen I am bid. Thank you very much.
有人出十五法郎，谢谢
Yes, 20 from you, sir. Thank you very much.
这位先生出二十法郎，十分感谢
- Twenty-five.  - Twenty-five on my right.
- 二十五法郎   - 目前出价二十五法郎
Thank you, madam.
谢谢您夫人
Twenty-five I am bid.
二十五法郎
Thirty? 30.
现在竞价三十法郎？
Selling at 30 francs, then.
三十法郎准备售出
Thirty once, 30 twice...
三十法郎一次，三十法郎两次
Sold for 30 francs
成交，三十法郎
to the Vicomte de Chagny.
夏尼伯爵得标
Thank you very much, sir.
谢谢您，先生
每一个细节都如同她的描述...
♪ A collector's piece indeed
她时常提起你，我的朋友....
♪ Every detail exactly as she said
提起你那天鹅绒的内衬和铅制的小雕像...
♪ She often spoke of you, my friend
待到我们都离开人世
♪ Your velvet lining and your figurine of lead
你依然会继续奏乐吗？
♪ Will you still play  when all the rest of us are dead? ♪
Lot 666, then.
接下来，第666号拍卖品
A chandelier in pieces.
破碎的大吊灯
Some of you may recall the strange affair  of The Phantom of the Opera,
应该还有人记得歌剧魅影的灵异事件吧
a mystery never fully explained.
至今尚未解开的谜团
We are told, ladies and gentlemen,  that this is the very chandelier
各位女士各位先生
that figures in that famous disaster.
据说这就是当年那场大灾难现场的吊灯
Our workshops have restored it
我们的工匠将其修复
and fitted parts of it with wiring  for the new electric light,
并且装上了新式电灯泡
so that we may get a hint  of how it may look when reassembled.
如此一来，我们便可大致重现它当年的风采
Perhaps we may even frighten away  the ghost of so many years ago
with a little illumination, gentlemen!
或许我们能够凭借这微弱的灯光   驱赶当年这剧院中的鬼魅
先生们 请看
歌剧魅影-阿尔伯特音乐厅
25周年纪念演出
第一幕 巴黎 1881年
This Trophy
♪这件战利品
第一场 夏拉莫的歌剧《汉尼拔》 预演
From our saviours
这件战利品 由我们的援军
由我们的援军
Of Rome
从奴役我们的罗马军队夺来
CHORUS:   With feasting and dancing and song
盛宴，舞蹈，歌咏
Tonight in celebration
今夜我们相聚于此庆祝胜利
We greet the victorious throng
欢迎胜利荣归的战士
Returned to bring salvation
为拯救我们回到此地
The trumpets of Carthage resound
迦太基的号角再度响起
Hear Romans now and tremble
听啊，罗马人，颤抖吧
Hark to our step on the ground
听听我们雄健的步伐    听听我们震天的战鼓
Hear the drums, Hannibal comes
汉尼拔来了
Sad to return to find the land we love
回到这片我们热爱的土地
Threatened once more  by Roma's far-reaching grasp...
悲伤的发现它再次受到威胁   罗曼远征军长驱直入
No, no, no, no!
不不不，不对
Signor, if you please.
阁下，麻烦您发音“罗马”好吗
- "Rome". We say "Rome", not "Roma".  - (ALL MURMURING)
我们说“罗马”不说“罗曼”
"Rome"? "Rome" is very hard for me.
罗马，罗马 对我来说有点难度
Well, once again, if you please, signor,  "Sad to return..."
麻烦您阁下，从“回到这片土地”开始重来一遍
- It's very, very hard. I am from Italy.  - Just get it right, please.
- 这非常，非常难，我来自意大利   - 请做好
PIANGI: Rome. Signor...
罗马，阁下请
Sad to return to find the land we love
回到这片我们热爱的土地
Threatened once more  by Rome's far-reaching grasp
悲伤地发现它再次受到罗马远征军的威胁
Tomorrow we shall  break the chains of Rome
明天我们将打破罗马人的枷锁
Tonight, rejoice
今夜，让我们狂欢吧
Your army
我们的军队
Has come home
回家了
Bid welcome to Hannibal's guests
欢迎汉尼拔的客人
The elephants of Carthage
迦太基的巨象
As guides on our conquering quests
指引着我们的征服之路
Dido sends
狄多女王（迦太基城的建立者）
Hannibal's friends
送来了汉尼拔的朋友
Once more to my welcoming arms
我张开双臂再次
My love returns in splendour
迎接吾爱在荣耀中回归
Once more to the sweetest of charms
我的心与灵魂再次
My heart and soul surrender
向那绝世风采臣服
The trumpeting elephants sound
听，那巨象的怒号
Hear Romans now and tremble
罗马人，颤抖吧
Hark to their step on the ground
听听我们雄健的步伐
Hear the drums
听听我们震天的战鼓
Hannibal comes
汉尼拔来了
REYER: Hey! Hey! We're doing that all again!
我们重来了一遍！
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
You were very good.  This song is marvellous. Thank you.
真是天籁之音，这音乐棒极了，谢谢
LEFEVRE: This way, gentlemen, this way.  REYER: Girls!
阁下，这边请
Rehearsals, as you see, are underway
如您所见，我们正在彩排
for a new production  of Chalumeau's Hannibal.
新版的夏拉莫歌剧《汉尼拔》
Ladies and gentlemen...
各位女士各位先生
(CLEARING THROAT)  Ladies and gentlemen, please...
女士们先生们，请注意
Ladies and...
女士们先生们
Madame Giry.
吉里夫人
Thank you.
劳驾你们
May I have your attention, please?
请注意听我说
As you know, for some weeks  there have been rumours
这几周，各位或许听到传闻说
about my imminent retirement.
我即将退休
I can now tell you, these were all true,
现在我可以告诉各位，传言属实
and it is now my pleasure to introduce you  to the two gentlemen
在此我很荣幸为大家介绍这两位
who now own the Opera Populaire,
我们剧院的新老板
Monsieur Richard Firmin  and Monsieur Giles André.
理查德·弗明先生和吉勒斯·安德烈先生
- (ALL APPLAUDING)  - ANDRÉ: Oh, no, please.
谢谢，哦别这样
Gentlemen, Signora Carlotta Giudicelli,
先生们，这位是卡洛塔·茱蒂雪莉夫人
our leading soprano for 19 seasons now.
我们剧院连任十九季的首席女高音
Of course, of course, I have experienced  all your greatest roles, signora.
当然，当然   我欣赏过您饰演的全部伟大角色，夫人
And Signor Ubaldo Piangi.
这位是乌巴尔多·皮安吉阁下
An honour, signor.
很荣幸，阁下
(CHUCKLES) If I remember rightly,  Elissa has a rather fine aria
如果我没记错
in Act Three of Hannibal.
伊莉莎(即狄多女王)在《汉尼拔》第三幕有一首精彩的咏叹调
I wonder, signora, if, as a personal favour,  you would oblige us with a private rendition?
我想向夫人提一个不情之请   您是否可以为我们私下表演一曲？
Unless, of course, Monsieur Reyer objects...
除非雷耶先生先生反对...
No, my manager commands!
如果我的经理命令我  雷耶先生？
My diva commands.  Would two bars be sufficient introduction?
既然我的女高音命令  试唱两小节是否足够了？
Two bars will be quite sufficient.
两小节足矣
REYER: Signora?
夫人请
Think of me
想念我
Think of me fondly
深情地想念我
When we've said goodbye
在我们分开之后
Remember me
记得时常
Every so often
想念我
Promise me you'll try
请答应我，你会尝试
On that day, that not so distant day
到那天 不久后的那一天
When you are far away and free
你离我而去 无拘无束
If you ever find a moment
若是偶尔有那么一瞬间
Spare a thought for me
请你仍然
Think of me
想起我
Think of me warmly...
想念我，温暖地想着我
He's here, The Phantom of the Opera
他来了，歌剧魅影
He's there, The Phantom of the Opera
CHORUS:  He is with us  It's the ghost
他就在这里，剧院里的幽灵
Good heavens, will you show a little courtesy!
天啊，麻烦你们有点礼数吧
Mademoiselle, please!
拜托，小姐
LEFEVRE: Signora! Are you all right?  Buquet! Where is Buquet?
夫人，你没事吧？  布凯呢，布凯在哪儿
Get that man down here!
让那家伙下来
Buquet, chief of the flys.  He's responsible for this.
布凯   这是台塔技术主管，这事得由他负责
Buquet! For God's sake, man,  what's going on up there?
布凯，天啊，到底那上面出什么状况了？
Please, monsieur, don't look at me
先生请别这么看我
As God's my witness, I was not at my post
上帝作证，我根本不在岗上
Please, monsieur, there's no one there
先生，那儿真的没有人在
And if there is,  well, then, it must be a ghost
如果要说有谁在的话，那只会是幽灵
He's there, The Phantom of the Opera
他在那儿，歌剧魅影...
Good heavens!  I have never known such insolence.
天啊，你们都鬼迷心窍了吗？
Signora, please.
夫人，拜托
(SCOFFS) These things do happen.
难免有意外！
"These things do happen"?
难免有意外？
You have been here five minutes!  What do you know?
你们才来了不过五分钟，你们凭什么自以为是？
(SNIFFLING) Si, these things do happen,  all the time!
对哦，"难免有意外"，你们就会这句
For the past three years,  these things do happen.
过去这三年来，一直在发生意外 难免有意外
And did you stop them happening? No!
而你呢，防范住了吗？没有！
And you... You're as bad as him.
还有你，你也不是什么善类
"These things do happen."
"难免有意外"
Well, until you stop these things happening,
好吧，你们必须杜绝这样的意外再次发生
this thing does not happen!
绝对不准再发生类似的意外
Ubaldo, andiamo!
乌巴尔多，我们走
Amateurs!
疏于职守
I don't think there's much more I can do  to assist you, gentlemen. Good luck.
先生们，恐怕我也帮不上你们什么了
祝你们好运
If you need me, I  shall be in Frankfurt.
如果有需要，到法兰克福找我
(EXCLAIMING) But, monsieur...
但是先生
LEFEVRE: Move, please. Out of the way.
借过一下
La Carlotta will be back.
卡洛塔夫人会回来的吧
You think so, monsieur?
你觉得会吗，先生？
Yes.
会吧
I have a message, sir, from the Opera Ghost.
我这里有一封来自剧院幽灵的信，先生
Oh, God in heaven, you're all obsessed!
天啊，你们真是鬼迷心窍
He merely welcomes you to his opera house.
他欢迎你们来到他的剧院
Commands that you continue  to leave Box Five empty for his use,
并且要求你们继续为他保留五号包厢
and reminds you that his salary is due.
另外，提醒你们，到发薪时间了
His salary?
给他发薪？
Monsieur Lefevre paid him  20,000 francs a month.
拉斐尔先生以前都支付他每月两万法郎的薪水
Perhaps you could afford more,  with the Vicomte de Chagny as your patron.
现在你们有夏尼伯爵的资助或许可以支付更多吧
Madame, I had hoped to have made  that announcement myself.
夫人，这个消息应当由我来公布
Will the Vicomte be at the performance  this evening, monsieur?
伯爵今晚会来观看演出吗，先生？
In our box.
会来我们的包厢
Madame, who is the understudy for the role?
夫人，女主角的替补演员是谁？
There is no understudy, monsieur.  The production is new.
先生，没有替补演员 这部歌剧是新作
Christine Daaé could sing it, sir.
先生，克莉斯汀·戴耶可以演唱
A ballet girl?
伴舞女郎？
Well, she's been taking lessons  from a great teacher.
她一直师从一位高人
Oh, from whom?
哪位高人？
I don't know, sir.
我不知道他的名字，先生
Oh, not you as well. Can you believe it?
哦，你也不知道，难以置信！
A full house, and we have to cancel!
票都售光了，现在我们只能取消公演
Daaé? That's a curious name.
戴耶？似曾相识的姓氏
Any relation to the violinist?
不会和那位著名的小提琴家有什么关系吧？
My father, sir.
他是我的父亲，先生
Let her sing for you, monsieur.
让她试唱一段吧，先生
She has been well taught.
她学习的非常出色
Very well.
好吧
Oh, from the beginning  of the aria then, mam'selle.
小姐，从咏叹调开头起唱
Gentlemen, please.
先生们，请
Think of me
♪ 想念我
Think of me fondly
♪ 深情地想念我
When we've said goodbye
♪ 在我们分开之后
Remember me
♪ 记得
Every so often
♪ 时常想念我
Promise me you'll try
♪ 请答应我，你会尝试
André, this is doing nothing for my nerves.
安德烈，这可安抚不了我的紧张情绪
Don't fret, Firmin.
别急躁，淡定点
On that day, that not so distant day
♪ 到那天，不久后的那一天
When you are far away and free
♪ 你离我远去，无拘无束
If you ever find a moment
♪ 如果偶尔有那么一瞬间
Spare a thought for me
♪ 请你仍然想起我
REYER: Madame! Monsieur!
夫人！先生！
Thank you. Thank you so much.
谢谢，非常感谢
And though it's clear
♪ 尽管，我们明白
Though it was always clear
♪ 一直明白
That this was never meant to be
♪ 我们注定不会有结局
If you happen to remember
♪ 但若是你偶然忆起
Stop and think of me
♪ 请驻留片刻想念我
Think of August
♪ 想想
When the world was green
♪ 那满目青翠的八月
Don't think about the way
♪ 不要纠结于
Things might have been
♪ 世事难料
Think of me
♪ 想念我
Think of me waking
♪ 想着我醒来的模样
Silent and resigned
♪ 安静的，温顺的
Imagine me
♪ 想象着
Trying too hard
♪ 我努力试图
To put you from my mind
♪ 将你忘却
Think of me
♪ 想念我
Please say you'll think of me
♪ 请告诉我你会想念我
Whatever else you choose to do
♪ 不论你将做如何选择
There will never be a day
♪ 今后的时光
When I won't think of you
♪ 我将无时无刻不思念你...
Can it be?
是她吗？
Can it be Christine?
是克莉斯汀吗？
Brava! Brava!
太棒了！太棒了！
Long ago
很久以前
It seems so long ago
似乎是很久很久以前
How young and innocent we were
那时我们还年少无知
She may not remember me
或许她已经将我淡忘
But I remember her
而我却仍然记得她...
Flowers fade
♪ 娇艳的花朵会褪色
The fruits of summer fade
♪ 夏日的果实会凋落
They have their seasons
♪ 一岁一枯荣
So do we
♪ 我们亦如此
But please promise me
♪ 但是请答应我
That sometimes
♪ 偶尔
You will think
♪ 你也会想念
Of me
♪ 我
MAN: Brava! Brava!
太棒了！太棒了！
(MEN LAUGHING)
（幕布）请勿吸烟
Christine Daaé, that was unbelievable.
克莉斯汀·戴耶！真是难以置信..
Yes, you did well.
不错，你唱的很棒
He will be pleased.
他一定很高兴
And, you! You were a disgrace!
但是你们,你们太丢人了
Such ronds de jambes! Such temps de cuisse!
这就是你们的竖趾旋转？这就是你们的撷跃？
Come! We rehearse. Now!
来，我们重新排练！立刻开始！
PHANTOM:  Brava
精彩
Brava
Bravissima
相当精彩
MEG:  Christine
克莉斯汀
Christine
PHANTOM:  Christine
克莉斯汀...
Where in the world have you been hiding?
原来你是真人不露相
Really, you were perfect
说真的，你唱的很完美
I only wish I knew your secret
真希望我能分享你的秘密
Who is this new tutor?
你的新导师究竟是谁？
Father once spoke of an angel
家父曾经提及一位天使
I used to dream he'd appear
他时常出现在我的梦中
Now as I sing I can sense him
当我唱歌的时候，便会感觉到他的存在
And I know he's here
我知道他就在附近
Here in this room, he calls me softly
就在这个房间里，隐藏在某个角落
Somewhere inside, hiding
轻声呼唤着我
Somehow I know he's always with me
难以言喻，我感觉他一直在我身边
He, the unseen genius
他，是遁世的天才
I watched your face from the shadows
我在后台的阴影中注视着你的脸
Distant through all the applause
透过掌声，显得遥远又陌生
I hear your voice in the darkness
我在黑暗中听到你的声音
Yet the words aren't yours
但却不是你该说的言语
Angel of Music, guide and guardian
音乐天使，指引者，守护者
-  Grant to me your glory  -  Who is this angel?
- 请赐予我你的荣耀   - 这个天使是谁？
BOTH:  This Angel of Music hide no longer
音乐天使，勿再躲藏
Secret and strange angel
神秘而陌生的天使
-  He's with me even now  -  Your hands are cold
- 他就在我身边，此时此刻   - 你的双手冰凉
-  All around  -  Your face, Christine, it's white
- 就在我身边   - 克莉斯汀，你的脸色苍白
-  It frightens me   -  Don't be frightened
- 令我害怕   - 无需害怕
Meg Giry. Are you a dancer?
梅格·吉里，你是伴舞吧？
Then go and practice.
快去练习
My dear, I was asked to give you this.
亲爱的，有人让我把这个交给你
Thank you.
谢谢
"A red scarf. The attic. Little Lotte."
『红色围巾，阁楼，小洛蒂...』
第三场 克莉斯汀的化妆室
ANDRÉ: A tour de force!  There's no other way to describe it!
可谓绝技！难以言喻
What a relief! Not a single refund!
何等宽慰啊！没有一人退票！
Greedy.
真贪心
Richard, I think we've made  quite a discovery with Miss Daaé!
理查德，戴耶小姐是我们新发掘的奇葩
FIRMIN: Here we are, Monsieur Vicomte.
到了，伯爵先生
Gentlemen, if you wouldn't mind.
先生们，若是你们不介意的话
This is one visit I should prefer  to make unaccompanied.
请允许我单独去拜访戴耶小姐
As you wish, monsieur.
如您所愿，阁下
- They appear to have met before.  - (MEN LAUGHING)
他们似乎是旧相识
Christine Daaé, where is your red scarf?
克莉斯汀·戴耶，你的红色围巾在哪里？
- Monsieur?  - Well, you can't have lost it.
- 阁下？   - 你该不会弄丢了吧？
After all the trouble I took.
我为它费了那么大劲
I was just 14 and soaked to the skin...
那年我十四岁，浑身湿透
Because you had run into the sea  to fetch my scarf.
因为你跳进海里去捞我的红色围巾
- Oh, Raoul. So it is you.  - Christine.
- 哦，真的是你，拉乌尔   - 克莉斯汀
Little Lotte, let her mind wander
『小洛蒂心存疑问』
You remember that, too?
你还记得...
Little Lotte thought, am I fonder of dolls
『小洛蒂心想：我喜欢洋娃娃呢』
BOTH:  Or of goblins, of shoes
『还是小精灵，又或是鞋子？』
Or of riddles, of frocks
『还是喜欢谜语，或者礼服』
Those picnics in the attic.
我们在阁楼上扮家家酒
Or of chocolates?
『还是喜欢巧克力呢』
Father playing the violin.
父亲拉着小提琴
As we read to each other  dark stories of the north. (LAUGHS)
我们则互说着北欧的阴暗故事.....
"No, what I love best," Lotte said
小洛蒂说：『都不是，我最喜欢的是...』
"Is when I'm asleep in my bed
『当我上床入睡的时候』
"And the Angel of Music  sings songs in my head
『音乐天使在我的脑海中歌唱』
BOTH:  "The Angel of Music  sings songs in my head"
音乐天使在我的脑海中歌唱
Father said, "When I'm in heaven, child,
父亲曾说：『孩子，我若是去往天堂』
"I will send the Angel of Music to you."
『便会将音乐天使派往你身边』
Well, Father is dead, Raoul,
拉乌尔，我的父亲已经过世
and I have been visited by the Angel of Music.
音乐天使真的来探访过我
No doubt of it. And now, we go to supper.
当然如此，那么现在，我们共进晚餐吧
No, Raoul, the Angel of Music is very strict.
不，拉乌尔，音乐天使教导严厉
- I shan't keep you up late.  - No...
我不会耽误你太晚的
You must change. I must get my hat.
走吧，你得更衣，我去拿礼帽
Two minutes... Little Lotte.
两分钟，小洛蒂
Raoul!
拉乌尔
Things have changed, Raoul.
物是人非了，拉乌尔
PHANTOM:   Insolent boy, the slave of fashion
傲慢的男孩，浮华的奴隶
Basking in your glory
陶醉于你的荣耀
Ignorant fool, this brave young suitor
无知的蠢物，这年轻大胆的追求者
Sharing in my triumph
竟敢分享我的胜利成果
Angel, I hear you  Speak, I listen
天使，我在聆听，请说，我在聆听
Stay by my side, guide me
请陪伴我，指引我
Angel, my soul was weak, forgive me
天使，我的意志薄弱，请原谅我...
Enter at last, master
你终于来了，导师
PHANTOM:   Flattering child, you shall know me
乖巧的孩子，你该明白我
See why in shadow I hide
明白我为何藏于阴影
Look at your face in the mirror
看看镜中的自己
I am there inside
我就在镜中
Angel of Music, guide and guardian
音乐天使，指引者，守护者
Grant to me your glory
请赐予我你的荣耀
Angel of Music, hide no longer
音乐天使，勿再躲藏
Come to me, strange angel
请来我身边，奇特的天使...
I am your Angel of Music
我就是你的音乐天使....
Come to me, Angel of Music
来我身边，音乐天使
I am your Angel of Music
我就是你的音乐天使
Come to me, Angel of Music
来我身边，音乐天使
Christine!
克莉斯汀？
第四场 地下迷宫
In dreams he came
♪ 梦境中他近我身旁
That voice which calls to me
♪ 他的声音召唤着我
And speaks my name
♪ 喃喃轻诉我的名字
And do I dream again
♪ 我是否又重回梦境
For now I find
♪ 此时此刻我才发现
The Phantom of the Opera is there
♪ 歌剧魅影就在这里
Inside my mind
♪ 潜伏在我心灵深处
Sing once again with me
♪ 再次与我一起
Our strange duet
♪ 同唱这奇妙的旋律
My power over you
♪ 我笼罩着你的力量
Grows stronger yet
♪ 变得日益强大
And though you turn from me
♪ 尽管你欲转身而去
To glance behind
♪ 禁不住要回眸一瞥
The Phantom of the Opera is there
♪ 歌剧魅影就在这里
Inside your mind
♪ 潜伏在你心灵深处
Those who have seen your face
♪ 见过你真面目的人
Draw back in fear
♪ 他们在恐惧中却步
I am the mask you wear
♪ 我是你所戴的面具
It's me they hear
♪ 人们听到其实是我
My spirit and your voice
♪ 我的灵魂你的声音
In one combined
♪ 紧紧结合成为一体
The Phantom of the Opera is there
♪ 歌剧魅影就在这里
He's there,  The Phantom of the Opera
♪ 他就是那歌剧魅影
Beware, The Phantom of the Opera
♪ 歌剧魅影就在这里
In all your fantasies
♪ 在你所有的幻想中
You always knew
♪ 你始终都心如明镜
That man and mystery
♪ 那个男人，那个魅影
Were both in you
♪ 其实同存于你心中
BOTH:  And in this labyrinth
♪ 在这重重迷宫之中
Where night is blind
♪ 如同夜色一般黑暗
The Phantom of the Opera is there
♪ 歌剧魅影就在这里
Inside my mind
♪ 潜伏在我心灵深处
My Angel of Music!
♪ 我的音乐天使
He's there, The Phantom of the Opera
♪ 他在这里，剧院魅影
- Sing!  - (VOCALISING)
歌唱吧
Sing!
Sing for me!
为我歌唱吧
第五场 夜之乐章
I have brought you
♪ 我带领你登上
To the seat of sweet music's throne
♪ 甜美的音乐宝座
To this kingdom  where all must pay homage to music
♪ 在这国度，人人都必须臣服于音乐
Music
♪ 音乐...
You have come here
♪ 你来到此地
For one purpose and one alone
♪ 只为一个目的
Since the moment I first heard you sing
♪ 自从我第一次听到你的歌声
I have needed you with me to serve me
♪ 我便知道我需要你在身边
To sing for my music
♪ 为我效力，为我歌唱
My music
♪ 我的音乐...
Night-time sharpens Heightens each sensation
♪ 深夜感触愈加敏锐
Darkness stirs And wakes imagination
♪ 暗潮翻滚，想象活跃
Silently the senses Abandon their defenses
♪ 无声无息，释放感觉
Slowly, gently Night unfurls its splendour
♪ 徐徐，缓缓，夜之炫魅舒展
Grasp it, sense it Tremulous and tender
♪ 感受，品味，温柔暗夜轻颤
Turn your face away From the garish light of day
♪ 躲避白昼刺目光芒
Turn your thoughts away From cold, unfeeling light
♪ 思绪逃离冷漠日光
And listen to the music Of the night
♪ 侧耳聆听夜之乐章
Close your eyes and surrender To your darkest dreams
♪ 闭目臣服幽深梦境
Purge your thoughts Of the life you knew before
♪ 洗尽心中红尘往事
Close your eyes Let your spirit start to soar
♪ 闭目随心，自由翱翔
And you'll live As you've never lived before
♪ 过眼云烟，恍若隔世
Softly, deftly Music shall surround you
♪ 轻柔，灵巧，音乐给你安抚
Hear it, feel it Closing in around you
♪ 聆听，感受，任由自己沉醉
Open up your mind Let your fantasies unwind
♪ 敞开心扉，放纵幻想
In this darkness
♪ 置身如此无边阴闇
Which you know you cannot fight
♪ 勿需抗拒
The darkness of the music Of the night
♪ 夜之乐章
Let your mind start a journey  through a strange new world
♪ 让心灵起航崭新旅程
Leave all thoughts of the world  you knew before
♪ 将前尘旧事抛诸身后
Let your soul Take you where you long to be
♪ 跟从灵魂，最深处的渴望
Only then Can you belong  To me
♪ 只有那时，你才心属于我
Floating, falling Sweet intoxication
♪ 飘荡，沉浮，迷醉不知归路
Touch me, trust me Savour each sensation
♪ 靠近，信任，感触逐一细品
Let the dream begin
♪ 让梦境开场，任暗夜笼罩
Let your darker side give in To the power of the music That I write
♪ 臣服于我谱写之乐章
The power of the music Of the night
♪ 魔力无穷的夜之乐章
You alone can make My song take flight
♪ 唯你能给它插上翅膀
Help me make the music Of the Night
♪ 助我共谱这夜之乐章
第六场 翌日清晨
I remember there was mist
我记得那时弥漫着薄雾
Swirling mist upon a vast, glassy lake
笼罩在宽阔似镜的湖面
There were candles all around
四周点燃无数蜡烛
And on the lake there was a boat
一叶扁舟飘荡其间
And in the boat there was a man
一位男子立于船沿
Who was that shape in the shadows?
阴影之中此人为谁
Whose is that face in the mask?
面具之下谁的面容
Damn you! You little prying Pandora
该死的   你这好奇的潘多拉
You little demon  Is this what you wanted to see?
你这小恶魔   这就是你想要看到的吗
Curse you!  - (YELLS)
诅咒你
You little lying Delilah!
你这妖妇大利拉
You little viper
你这蛇蝎美人
Now you cannot ever be free
从此你将永世为囚
Damn you!
该死的
Curse you!
诅咒你
Stranger than you dreamt it
比你梦想中更怪异
Can you even dare to look
从此你还敢看我一眼吗
Or bear to think of me
或是能忍受想起我的感觉吗
This loathsome gargoyle who burns in hell
我这丑陋的怪物  受地狱业火的煎熬
But secretly yearns for heaven
却偷偷向往着天堂
Secretly, secretly
偷偷地，偷偷地
But, Christine
可是，克莉斯汀
Fear can turn to love
恐惧或许能转变成爱恋
You'll learn to see
你会了解和发现
To find the man behind the monster
怪物外表下这个人
This repulsive carcass
这具令人恶心的躯体
Who seems a beast
有着野兽一般的外表
But secretly dreams of beauty
内心却偷偷渴望美好
Secretly, secretly
偷偷地，偷偷地
Oh, Christine...
哦，克莉斯汀
Come, we must return
走吧，我必须送你回去
Those two fools who run my theatre  will be missing you
经营我剧院的那两个傻子会发现你失踪了
第七场 后台
快 来这边
Like yellow parchment is his skin
他的皮肤像蜡黄的羊皮纸卷
A great black hole serves as the nose  which never grew
他生来就没有鼻子只剩黑洞
You must be always on your guard
你们必须时时刻刻小心谨慎
Or he will catch you with his magical lasso
否则他会用魔法套索圈住你
GIRY:  Those who speak of what they know
那些自以为是散布谣言的人
Find too late that prudent silence is wise
待到懂得沉默是金为时已晚
Joseph Buquet hold your tongue
约瑟夫·布凯，闭上你的嘴
He will burn you with the heat of his eyes
不然他会用目光灼烧你
(LAUGHS)
第八场 经理办公室
"Mystery after gala night"
盛会之夜的神秘事件
It says, "Mystery of soprano's flight"
这里说『主唱女高音不翼而飞』
"Mystified," baffled Sûreté say
『令人疑惑，让人费解』
"We are mystified  We suspect foul play"
『我们困惑不解，我们怀疑其中有诈!』
Bad news on soprano scene
女高音的出场总伴随着流言蜚语
First Carlotta, now Christine
先有卡洛塔，后有克莉斯汀
Still, at least the seats get sold
不过没事，座无虚席
Gossip's worth its weight in gold
流言蜚语能带来利润
Diva tenders resignation
女主唱辞演
Cover does a moonlight flit
备角不知去向
Half your cast disappears,  but the crowd still cheers
半数演员失踪   观众还是一样叫好
Opera, to hell with Gluck and Handel
这就是歌剧！去他的格鲁克和韩德尔
Have a scandal and you're sure to have a hit
有丑闻炒作，就必然卖座
Damnable, will they all walk out?
该死的！难道大家都出逃成瘾？
This is damnable
真该死！
安德烈，别嚷嚷
André, please don't shout  It's publicity
And the take is vast  Free publicity
这只是炒作！而且利润不菲，这是免费的宣传
But we have no cast
但是巧妇难为无米之炊，演员都跑了
But, André, have you seen the queue?
安德烈，看看那排队购票的长龙
Oh, it seems you've got one, too
哦，貌似你也收到了
"Dear André, what a charming gala
尊敬的安德烈阁下，盛会举办如此之成功！
"Christine enjoyed a great success
克莉斯汀表现非同凡响
"We were hardly bereft when Carlotta left
卡洛塔离开也无伤大雅
"Otherwise, the chorus was entrancing
顺带一提，合唱令人陶醉
"But the dancing was a lamentable mess"
可惜伴舞惨不忍睹
"Dear Firmin, just a brief reminder
尊敬的弗明阁下，稍加提醒
"My salary has not been paid
我的薪水还未支付
"Send it care of the Ghost by return of post
请直接交给鬼魅 请立即回复PTO（歌剧魅影）
"PTO, no one likes a debtor
没人喜欢欠债的人
"So it's better if my orders are obeyed"
希望阁下遵从指示
BOTH:   Who would have the gall to send this?
是谁胆敢寄送这样的信？
Someone with a puerile brain
简直是痴心妄想！
These are both signed "O.G."   Who the hell is he?
- 两份信皆署名OG（剧院鬼魅）   - 他到底是谁？
BOTH:  Opera Ghost
剧院鬼魅！
-  It's really not amusing  -  He's abusing our position
- 这实在是太离谱   - 竟然侮辱我们的身份
-  In addition he wants money  -  He's a funny sort of spectre
- 他还想要骗取钱财   - 真是无理取闹的幽灵
BOTH:  To expect a large retainer  Nothing plainer
指望不劳而获，坐享高薪
He is clearly quite insane
他完全就是个疯子
-  Where is she?  -  You mean Carlotta?
- 她在哪儿？   - 你说卡洛塔？
I mean Miss Daaé  Where is she?
我说戴耶小姐，她在哪儿？
-  Well, how should we know?  -  I want an answer
- 我们怎么会知道   - 我要一个答案
-  I take it that you sent me this note  -  What's all this nonsense?
- 该不会是你们写的这封信吧？   - 无稽之谈
-  Of course not  -  Don't look at us
- 显然不是   - 别怀疑我们！
-  She's not with you then?  -  Of course not
- 那么她没和你们在一起喽？   - 当然没有
-  We're in the dark  -  Monsieur, don't argue
- 我们一无所知   - 先生们，别狡辩
Isn't this the letter you wrote?
这封信果真不是你们写的吗？
And what is it  that we're meant to have wrote?
我们『作』的信什么内容？
Written?
『写』信
"Do not fear for Miss Daaé
无须担心戴耶小姐
"The Angel of Music has her under his wing
音乐天使置其于羽翼之下
"Make no attempt to see her again"
不要试图再见到她
Well, if you didn't write it, who did?
若不是你们，还有谁会这样做？
Where is he?
他在哪儿
-  Ah, welcome back  -  Your precious patron
- 哦，欢迎回来   - 尊贵的赞助人
-  Where is he?  -  What is it now?
- 他在哪儿   - 又怎么了？
I have your letter  A letter which I rather resent
我收到你的信  令人十分反感的信
-  Did you send it?  -  Of course not
- （费明）是你寄的吗？   - （拉乌尔）当然不是
ANDRÉ:  As if he would  -  You didn't send it?
- （费明）那如果不是他   - 不是你寄的？
-  Of course not  -  What's going on?
- 当然不是   - 究竟什么情况？
You dare to tell me  that this is not the letter you sent?
你敢说不是你寄的？
And what is it that I'm meant to have sent?
究竟什么内容？
"Your days at the Opera Populaire  are numbered
你在剧院气数已尽
"Christine Daaé will be singing  on your behalf tonight
克莉斯汀·戴耶今夜将代替你演出
"Be prepared for a great misfortune
若你试图阻挠
"Should you attempt to take her place"
必将大难临头
BOTH:  Far too many notes for my taste
我可受不了这么频繁的匿名信
And most of them about Christine
而且几乎都和克莉斯汀有关
All we've heard since we came  is Miss Daaé's name
从我们接管以来，听到的都是戴耶小姐的名字
Miss Daaé has returned
戴耶小姐回来了
In which case I think  our meeting is adjourned
那么我们的谈话可以告一段落了
Where precisely is she now?
她究竟在哪里？
I thought it best that she went home
我想最好让她回房
She needed rest
她需要休息
May I see her?
我可以去见见她吗？
No, monsieur, she will see no one
恐怕不行，先生，她谁也不想见
Will she sing?   Will she sing?
她会唱吗？她会唱吗？
Here, I have a note
我这里有一封信
ALL:  Let me see it   -  Please!
- 让我看看   - 拜托
"Gentlemen, I have now sent you  several notes of the most amiable nature,
各位先生，我已经寄出多封出自善意的手信
"detailing how my theatre is to be run."
详细说明了应当如何经营我的剧院
"You have not followed my instructions."
然而你们并未听从我的指引
- "I shall give you one last chance..."  - PHANTOM: I shall give you one last chance:
最后再给你们一次机会
Christine Daaé has returned to you
克莉斯汀·戴耶已经送回
And I am anxious  her career should progress
我期待她的演艺事业蒸蒸日上
In the new production of El Muto
在新作《哑仆》里
You will therefore cast Carlotta  as the pageboy
你们要让卡洛塔饰演随从
And put Miss Daaé in the role of Countess
让戴耶小姐饰演伯爵夫人
The role which Miss Daaé plays  calls for charm and appeal
戴耶小姐的角色，需要有迷人的风采
The role of the pageboy is silent
随从的角色，将不需要台词
Which makes my casting, in a word, ideal
如此选角，在我看来十分理想
I shall watch the performance  from my normal seat in Box Five,
我还会如往常一般   坐在五号包厢内欣赏演出
which will be kept empty for me:
须为我保留席位
- Should these commands be ignored...  - "Should these commands be ignored,
若无视我的指示
"a disaster beyond your imagination  will occur.
将发生你们意想不到的灾难
"I remain, gentlemen,  your obedient servant, O.G."
到目前为止，各位先生   我仍是你们忠诚的仆从  OG（剧院鬼魅）敬上
Christine, Christine
克莉斯汀 克莉斯汀
-  Christine!  -  Whatever next
- 克莉斯汀!   - 接下来会如何？
It's all a ploy to help Christine
这些都是帮助克莉斯汀上位的『鬼』计
-  This is insane  -  I know who sent this
- 简直疯了   - 我知道是谁干的
The Vicomte, her lover
就是子爵先生，她的旧情人！
Indeed? Can you believe this?
此话当真？难以置信！
-  Signora!  -  How can you do this?
夫人
O traditori  O mentitori
什么都不会改变
-  Signora!  -  You are our star
- 夫人   - 你是我们的明星
And always will be
以后也将一直是我们的明星
-  Signora!  -  The man is mad
- 夫人   - 这个人疯了
-  We don't take orders  -  Miss Daaé will be playing the pageboy
- 我们不会听命于他   - 戴耶小姐将扮演
The silent role
没有台词的随从角色
Carlotta will be playing the lead
卡洛塔将领衔主演
You don't deserve her!
你们不配让她为你们出演
-  It's useless trying to appease me  -  Appease her
想安抚我是白费力气
-  You're only saying this to please me  -  To please her
- 你们只是想取悦我   - 取悦她
Signori, è vero?
夫人，拜托
BOTH:  No, no, non voglio udire!  Lasciatemi morire!
不，不，我不想听
O Padre mio! Dio!
哦父亲！哦上帝！
Who scorn his word, beware to those
（吉里）蔑视他的人，要小心了
The Angel sees   Why did Christine fly from my arms?
天使看的见，天使会知道
The Angel knows   You have rebuked me
- 天使会知道   - （卡洛塔）你们在责难我
MANAGERS:  Signora, pardon us
夫人，原谅我们
You have replaced me
你们撤换了我！
BOTH:  Please, signora, we beseech you
拜托，夫人，我们恳请您
GIRY:  This hour shall see your darkest fears  -  I must see her
此时终于知道你最惧怕的是什么   （拉乌尔）我必须去见克莉斯汀
The Angel knows  The Angel hears
天使会知道，天使听得见
Abbandonata, desiderata  O, sventura, disgraziata
（卡洛塔）抛弃我！我这代罪羔羊！
Signora, sing for us
夫人，为我们歌唱
-  Abbandonata  -  Don't be unfeeling
- 抛弃   - 别无动于衷
-  What new surprises are in store?  -  Our star
我们的明星
Your public needs you
你的观众们需要你
We need you, too
我们也需要你
Would you not rather  have your precious little ingénue?
难道你们不想启用那位宝贝新人？
BOTH:  Signora, no
当然不，夫人
The world wants you
整个世界只为你一人喝彩
Prima donna, first lady of the stage
舞台上的第一夫人，首席女高音
Your devotees are on their knees  to implore you
你的崇拜者都跪求着你引吭高歌
Can you bow out  when they're shouting your name?
他们呼唤着你的名字  难道你忍心就此谢幕
Think of how they all adore you
想想他们是多么爱戴你
Prima donna, enchant us once again
首席女高音，再次让我们陶醉吧
Think of your muse
想想你的音乐天赋
And of the queues round the theatre
想想剧院外翘首以盼的观众
Can you deny us the triumph in store?
难道你要将近在眼前的辉煌拒之门外？
Sing, prima donna, once more
歌唱吧，再次歌唱吧，首席女高音
RAOUL:  Christine spoke of an angel
克莉斯汀提过一位天使
Prima donna, your song shall live again
首席女高音，让你的声音再次回荡剧院
You took a snub   Think of your public
你或许遭受了冷落
But there's a public who needs you
但是观众们需要你
Those who hear your voice  liken you to an angel
那些听过你天使之音的人
Think of their cry of undying support  RAOUL:  Is this the Angel of Music?
- 想想那些无尽支持的欢呼   - 这就是音乐天使？
We get our opera
（安德烈）我们的歌剧顺利演出
She gets her limelight   Follow where the limelight leads you
（弗明）她得到万众瞩目，请追随聚光灯吧
Prima donna, your song will never die
首席女高音，你的歌声永不磨灭
You'll sing again  and to an unending ovation
你将再次献唱，喝彩不绝于耳
Think how you'll shine in that final encore
想想在终场安可中你将会如何光芒四射
Sing, prima donna, once more
歌唱吧，再次歌唱吧，首席女高音
ALL:  ...demands are rejected
我必须亲眼看到你们拒绝这些要求！
Who'd believe a diva  happy to relieve a chorus girl
谁会相信歌剧女主角会输给
Who's gone and slept with the patron?
靠取悦赞助人妄图上位的伴舞女郎
Raoul and the soubrette  entwined in love's duet
拉乌尔和那轻浮女人，缠绵于热恋之中
Although he may demur  He must have been with her
他或许会否认，但他肯定是跟戴耶小姐在一起
You'd never get away with all this in a play
这种事在这个圈子里时有发生
But if it's loudly sung  and in a foreign tongue
但若高声唱出，换一种语言   他就回天乏术了
It's just the sort of story audiences adore
这就如同一个故事
In fact a perfect opera   For if his curse is on this opera
一场完美戏剧
Prima donna, the world is at your feet
首席女高音，整个世界臣服在你脚下
A nation waits  and how it hates to be cheated
国人翘首以盼，莫要叫他们失望
Light up the stage with that age-old rapport
用那往昔和谐的表演，照亮这整个舞台
Sing, prima donna
歌唱吧，再次歌唱吧，首席女高音
Once more
再次歌唱吧
PHANTOM: So, it is to be war between us.
那么，我们之间的战争即将开始
If these demands are not met,
既然这些要求都遭到无视
a disaster beyond imagination will occur!
你们将遭受意想不到的灾难
ALL:  Once more
再次歌唱
第九场 阿尔布里泽之《哑仆》演出现场
RAOUL: Gentlemen, if you would care to take  your seats? We shall be sitting in Box Five.
先生们，是否可以请你们入席？我们应该坐在五号包厢里
ANDRÉ: Do you really think  that's wise, monsieur?
先生，你真的觉得这是明智之举吗？
RAOUL: My dear André, there would appear  to be no seats available other than Box Five.
我亲爱的安德烈，貌似也确实没有其他的空位了
They say that this youth  has set my lady's heart aflame
据说，那位少年，让伯爵夫人欲火焚身
His Lordship sure would die of shock
伯爵大人若是知道一定怒发冲冠
His Lordship is a laughing stock
现在伯爵成了众人的笑柄
Should he suspect her, God protect her
若他怀疑夫人，夫人只能祈求上帝保佑了
ALL:  Shame, shame, shame
无耻！无耻！无耻！
This faithless lady's bound for Hades
不守妇道的夫人注定要下地狱
Shame, shame, shame
无耻！无耻！无耻
Serafimo, your disguise is perfect
塞拉菲莫，你的乔装很完美
Why, who can this be?
会是谁呢？
Gentle wife, admit your loving husband
好夫人，让你亲爱的丈夫进门吧
ANDRÉ: Every seat sold!
剧院满座
FIRMIN: Hardly a disaster  beyond imagination.
根本没发生意想不到的灾难
My love, I am called to England  on affairs of State
亲爱的夫人，我被派去英国商讨国家大事
And must leave you with your new maid
只能留你和你的新女仆在家了
Though I'd happily take the maid with me.  (LAUGHS MISCHIEVOUSLY)
尽管我很乐意带走这个女仆
The old fool's leaving. (LAUGHS)
傻老头子要走了
I suspect my young bride is untrue to me
我怀疑年轻的妻子对我不忠
I shall not leave but shall hide over there
我佯装离开，躲在附近
To observe her
暗中观察
Addio
再见
BOTH:  Addio
Serafimo, away with this pretence
塞拉菲莫，别再装了
You cannot speak
你不能言语
But kiss me in my husband's absence
但我丈夫不在的时候  你可以亲吻我
Poor fool, he makes me laugh  Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha
可怜的傻子，他真可笑
Time I tried to get a better, better half
我也该找个更好的伴侣了
ALL:  Poor fool, he doesn't know  Ho, ho, ho, ho, ho
可怜的傻瓜，还蒙在鼓里
If he knew the truth he'd never ever go
如果他知道了真相，必定不会善罢甘休
PHANTOM: (ANGRILY) Did I not instruct  that Box Five was to be kept empty?
难道我没有指示你们   为我预留五号包厢吗
He's here, The Phantom of the Opera
歌剧魅影来了
It's him, I know it. It's him.
是他，我知道就是他
- (MURMURING)  - Calm down.
镇静
Your part is silent, little toad!
你的角色没有台词，小癞蛤蟆！
PHANTOM: A toad, madame?
你叫她癞蛤蟆吗，夫人？
Perhaps it is you who are the toad.
恐怕你才是令人厌恶的癞蛤蟆
Maestro, da capo, per piacere.
指挥，重起
Serafimo, away with this pretence
塞拉菲莫，别再装了
You cannot speak, but kiss me in my...
你不能言语，但是你可以亲吻我呱
Poor fool, he makes me laugh  Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha
可怜的傻瓜，他真好笑   哈哈哈呱
PIANGI: Maestro! Maestro, no!
指挥，指挥，停下
PHANTOM: Behold!  She is singing to bring down the chandelier!
看呀！她的演唱人神共弃  都快要震落这华丽的吊灯
FIRMIN: Ladies and gentlemen, we apologise.
女士们先生们，我们十分抱歉
The performance will continue  in 10 minutes' time,
演出将在十分钟后继续
when the role of the Countess  will be sung by Miss Christine Daaé.
伯爵夫人的角色，将由戴耶小姐出演
Ladies and gentlemen! (PANTING)
女士们先生们
Oh: (LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)  In the meantime, ladies and gentlemen,
在这段时间里，女士们先生们
we shall be giving you the ballet...
我们为您献上芭蕾表演
...Three of tonight's opera.
今晚剧目的第三幕
Maestro, bring the ballet forward.
指挥，芭蕾表演
The ballet. Now!
芭蕾表演，现在开始
Ladies and gentlemen,  please remain in your seats.
女士们先生们，请稍安勿躁
Do not panic. It was an accident.
不要恐慌，这只是意外
Simply an accident.
单纯的意外
第十场 剧院天台
-  Why have you brought us here?  -  Don't take me back there
- 我们来这儿做什么？   - 别再回去了
-  We must return  -  He'll kill me
- 可我们必须回去   - 那他会杀了我
-  His eyes will find me there  -  Christine, don't say that
- 他的目光总会捕捉到我！   - 克莉斯汀，别危言耸听
-  Those eyes that burn  -  Don't even think it
- 他的双眼燃烧着怒火！   - 不要有这样可怕的念头
-  And if he has to kill a thousand men  -  Forget this waking nightmare
- 他不惜牺牲成百上千的人命   - 忘记这梦魇吧
-  The Phantom of the Opera will kill again  -  The Phantom is a fable
- 歌剧魅影会大开杀戒   - 歌剧魅影只是无稽之谈
Believe me,  there is no Phantom of the Opera
相信我  他会再度大开杀戒
My God, who is this man?   My God, who is this man?
上帝，这是谁
-  Who hunts to kill  -  This mask of death
- 上帝啊，究竟是谁伺机猎杀？   - 带着面具的死神
-  I can't escape from him  -  Whose is this voice you hear
- 我无法逃脱他 再也无法逃脱   - 你时时刻刻听到的声音是谁？
BOTH:  And in this labyrinth  where night is blind
在地下迷宫里  如夜一般的黑暗中
-  The Phantom of the Opera is here  -  The Phantom of the Opera is there
- 歌剧魅影就在那里   - 歌剧魅影就在那里
-  Inside my mind  -  Inside your mind
- 潜伏在我心灵深处   - 潜伏在你心灵深处
There is no Phantom of the Opera
没有所谓的歌剧魅影
Raoul, I've been there
拉乌尔，我曾经去过
To his world of unending night
去过他暗夜一般的世界
To a world where the daylight dissolves  into darkness
在那里，黑暗吞噬日光
Darkness
深沉如墨
Raoul, I've seen him
拉乌尔，我曾经见过他
Can I ever forget that sight?
我怎会忘却当时的景象
Can I ever escape from that face?
我如何能逃离那副面容
So distorted, deformed
如此扭曲，如此畸形
It was hardly a face in that darkness
几乎不能辨认的面容  隐藏在那黑暗之中
Darkness
黑暗
But his voice filled my spirit
然而他的声音奇妙而甜美
With a strange, sweet sound
滋润了我的灵魂
In that night there was music
在那晚，他的音乐
In my mind
闯入我心扉
And through music
我的心灵不禁
My soul began to soar
随着音乐飞舞
And I heard
我聆听着
-  As I'd never heard before  -  What you heard was
- 那是我从未听过的   - 你听到的
A dream and nothing more
不过是梦
Yet in his eyes
在他的眼中
All the sadness of the world
似乎聚集了全世界的悲伤
Those pleading eyes
那祈求的眼神
That both threaten
又是威胁
And adore
又是爱慕
Christine, Christine
克莉斯汀，克莉斯汀
PHANTOM:  Christine
克莉斯汀
What was that?
那是什么声音？
Christine, come here.
克莉斯汀，过来
No more talk of darkness
莫再提及那片黑暗
Forget these wide-eyed fears
忘却那份惊悚恐惧
I'm here, nothing will harm you
我保护你不再受伤
My words will warm and calm you
安抚让你温暖平静
Let me be your freedom
让我带你逃离恐惧
Let daylight dry your tears
让阳光拭去你的泪
I'm here, with you, beside you
我在这里就在身边
To guard you and to guide you
守护着你，给你指引
Say you'll love me every waking moment
清醒时，每分每秒说爱我
Turn my head with talk of summertime
畅谈夏日美好时光
Say you need me with you, now and always
说你需要我，此刻到永远
Promise me that all you say is true
发誓这都言自肺腑
That's all I ask of you
这是我对你唯一要求
Let me be your shelter
让我为你遮风挡雨
Let me be your light
让我为你照亮前途
You're safe, no one can find you
你很安全，无迹可寻
Your fears are far behind you
你的恐惧都已远远抛开
All I want is freedom
我所渴求的只是自由
A world with no more night
逃离黑夜，远离恐惧
And you always beside me
你将一直在我身边
To hold me and to hide me
将我拥抱，给我庇护
Then say you'll share with me one love One lifetime
你将与我分享一生，唯一的爱
Let me lead you from your solitude
让我来打开你的心扉
Say you need me with you  Here beside you
说你需要我永远陪在你身边
Anywhere you go, let me go, too
无论你所去何处  请让我与你同行
Christine, that's all I ask of you
克莉斯汀，这是我对你唯一所求
Say you'll share with me one love One lifetime
请说你将与我分享一生，唯一的爱
Say the word and I will follow you
请说出口来，我将永远跟随你
Share each day with me
陪伴我每一天
Each night, each morning
朝朝暮暮
Say you love me
请说你爱我
You know I do
你知我爱你
BOTH:  Love me
爱我
That's all I ask of you
是我对你唯一所求
Anywhere you go, let me go, too
无论你所去何处  请让我与你同行
Love me
爱我
That's all I ask Of you
是我对你唯一所求
I must go
我得走了
They'll wonder where I am  Wait for me, Raoul
他们会找我 等着我，拉乌尔
Christine, I love you
我爱你，克莉丝汀！
Order your fine horses
快去备好你的骏马
Be with them at the door
带它们在门口等我
And soon you'll be beside me
很快你将重归我怀
You'll guard me and you'll guide me
你会守护我指引我
I gave you my music
我给了你我的音乐
Made your song take wing
给你的歌声插上翅膀
And now How you've repaid me
如今你却如此回报我
Denied me and betrayed me
拒绝我，背叛我
He was bound to love you
他听到了你天籁之声
When he heard you sing
必然深深陷入爱恋
Christine...
克莉丝汀…克莉丝汀…
Say you'll share with me one love
请说你将与我分享
One lifetime
一生唯一的爱
Say the word
请说出口来
And I will follow you
我将永远跟随你
Share each day with me
陪伴你每一天
Each night, each morning
朝朝暮暮
You will curse the day you did not do
终有一天你将会悔不当初
All that the Phantom Asked of you
未能遵从歌剧魅影的要求
中场休息
第二幕：六个月以后
第一场：化妆舞会
Monsieur Firmin?
弗明先生？
Monsieur André?
安德烈先生？
Dear André, what a splendid party
安德烈啊，这真是场盛大的舞会！
The prologue to a bright new year
迎接灿烂新年的序曲
Quite a night, I'm impressed
如此令人难忘的一夜
Well, one does one's best
唉，我只是尽心尽力
BOTH:  Here's to us
敬我们
A toast to all the city
也敬这座城市！
Such a pity that The Phantom can't be here
只可惜那个魅影无法到场
ALL:  Masquerade
化妆舞会！
Paper faces on parade
假面舞者，盛装游行
Masquerade
化妆舞会！
Hide your face  so the world will never find you
遮住脸庞  世界便寻你不到
Masquerade
化妆舞会！
Every face a different shade
面孔各异！
Masquerade
化妆舞会！
Look around  There's another mask behind you
环顾你四周，身后还是张面具
Flash of mauve  Splash of puce
紫红荧光闪，深褐影飞散
Fool and king  Ghoul and goose
傻瓜与国王，恶鬼站鹅旁
Green and black  Queen and priest
淡绿与深黑，皇后与牧师
Trace of rouge  Face of beast
诡异胭脂红，野兽露面庞
Faces
面孔…
Take your turn  Take a ride
该你了！
On the merry-go-round  In an inhuman race
坐上旋转木马   开始一段无人的赛跑
-  Thigh of blue  -  True is false Who is who
- 金色眼睛，蓝色大腿   - 似真似假，谁又是谁
-  Swirl of gown  -  Ace of hearts
- 翘唇微启，长袍旋动   - 红心Ace， 小丑脸庞
ALL:  Faces
面孔…
Drink it in  Drink it up
喝了它，喝光它
Till you've drowned in the light
直到你醉倒在光影之间，声色之中
In the sound  BOTH:  But who can name the face?
谁能认出那张脸
ALL:  Masquerade
化妆舞会！
Grinning yellows  Spinning reds
金碧辉煌，万紫千红
Masquerade
化妆舞会
Take your fill
酒池肉林
Let the spectacle astound you
纸醉金迷
Masquerade
化妆舞会！
Burning glances  Turning heads
目光交汇，热情燃烧
Masquerade
化妆舞会
Stop and stare
驻足观望
At the sea of smiles around you
笑脸如潮
Masquerade
化妆舞会
Seething shadows  Breathing lies
人影攒动，若隐若现
Masquerade  You can fool
化妆舞会！
Any friend who ever knew you
人不识我，我不识人
Masquerade Leering satyrs  Peering eyes
化妆舞会！目光交织，眼神挑逗
Masquerade  Run and hide
化妆舞会！无论奔跑或躲藏
But the face will still pursue you
难逃追逐之面庞
ANDRÉ:  Makes you glad  -  Makes you proud
尽情舞会夜  尽兴妆后人
让你快乐！
-  All the créme de la créme  -  Watching us
让你骄傲！ 极乐中的极乐！
-  And watching them  -  And all our fears are in the past
看看别人 看看自己 往昔恐惧 已成云烟
CARLOTTA:  Of delight  ANDRÉ:  Of Elysian peace
平安无事
轻松愉快
天堂般安宁
And we can breathe at last
我们终于可以松口气
-  No more notes  -  No more ghost
- 没有信笺  - 没有幽灵
Here's a toast
共举杯
-  Here's a health  -  To a prosperous year
- 祝健康  -贺新年
-  To the new chandelier
敬这崭新的华丽吊灯
And may its splendour never fade
愿它永远闪耀光芒
What a change
终能重享欢悦  愿此不再改变
What a blessed release
多么大的天赐解脱
And what a masquerade
多么棒的化妆舞会
Think of it  A secret engagement
想想吧，秘密的订婚
Look, your future bride
看看你未来的新娘
Just think of it
想想吧
But why is it secret?  What have we to hide?
但为何要保密？这有何需隐瞒？
-  You promised me  -  You promised me
- 你答应我的   - 你答应我的
No, Raoul, please don't  They'll see
拉乌尔 请别这样
Well, let them see  It's an engagement, not a crime
让他们看吧 不过是订婚，又不是犯罪
Christine, what are you afraid of?
克莉丝汀，你怕什么？
-  Let's not argue  -  Let's not argue
- 我们别吵   - 我们别吵
-  Please pretend  -  I can only hope You will understand in time
先假装一下，日后你便会明白
I'll understand in time
我只能希望，日后我便会明白
Masquerade  Paper faces on parade
化妆舞会！假面舞者，盛装游行
Masquerade  Hide your face So the world will never find you
化妆舞会！ 遮住脸庞，世界便寻你不到
Masquerade Every face a different shade
化妆舞会！面孔皆各异
Masquerade Look around
化妆舞会！环顾你四周
There's another mask behind you
身后还是张面具
Masquerade Burning glances  Turning heads
化妆舞会！目光交汇，热情燃烧
Masquerade Stop and stare At the sea of smiles around you
化妆舞会！ 驻足观望，笑脸如潮
Masquerade Grinning yellows  Spinning reds
化妆舞会！ 金碧辉煌，万紫千红
Masquerade
化妆舞会！
Let the spectacle astound you
酒池肉林，纸醉金迷
Why so silent, good messieurs?
各位为何不言不语？
Did you think that I had left you for good?
难道以为我已消失？
Have you missed me, good messieurs?
各位可曾想念起我？
I have written you an opera
我为你们写了部新歌剧
Here I bring the finished score
特此带来完整曲谱
Don Juan Triumphant
『唐璜的胜利』
I advise you to comply
建议你们听从
My instructions should be clear
我的指示很清楚
Remember there are worse things  than a shattered chandelier
别忘了世上还有比吊灯坠落更糟的事
Your chains are still mine  You will sing for me
项链属于我，你还将为我歌唱
Madame Giry?
吉里夫人，吉里夫人…
Monsieur, don't ask me.
先生，别问我
I know no more than anyone else.
我知道的并不比别人多
That's not true.  You know something, don't you?
说谎，你一定知道点什么！
I know nothing.
我真的不知道！
Please, monsieur, don't ask me.
先生，请别再问了
Madame, for all our sakes.
夫人，请为大家着想
第二场 后台
Very well.
好吧
It was years ago.
那是很久以前的事了
There was a travelling fair in the city.
有个流浪的杂耍团来城里
Tumblers, conjurers, human oddities.
杂技演员，魔术师，各种怪人…
- Go on.  - And there was...
继续说下去
I shall never forget him.
我绝不会忘记…
A man locked in a cage.
那时有个人被锁在…笼子里
In a cage?
笼子里？
Aprodigy, monsieur.
他是位天才，先生！
Scholar, architect, musician.
学者，建筑师，音乐家
- A composer.  - And an inventor, too, monsieur.
- 也是位作曲家 -还是一位发明家，先生
They boasted he had once built  for the Shah of Persia a maze of mirrors.
传说他曾为波斯王建了个镜子迷宫
- Who was this man?
他是谁？
A freak of nature More monster than man
天生的畸形，不像人类，更像一头怪物
Deformed?
怪胎…？
- From birth it seemed.
从出生以来，好像就…
My God.
天哪
Then he went missing. He escaped
然后…他失踪了，逃跑了
Go on.
继续说
They never found him  It was said he had died
他们再也没找到他   传说他死了
But he didn't die, did he?
但是没死，对吗？
The world forgot him
世界遗忘了他
But I never can
但我不会…
-  For in this darkness I have seen him again  -  And so our phantom's this man?
- 在黑暗中，我又见到了他   - 我们的魅影就是他…
I have said too much, monsieur, too much.
- 我说的太多了，先生，太多了…   - 等等！
- No! Wait!  - And there have been too many accidents.
已经发生太多意外了，太多了…
Accidents? Madame Giry!
夫人！意外？！
吉里夫人！
第三场 经理的办公室
Ludicrous Have you seen the score?
荒唐！看了曲谱没？
Simply ludicrous
太荒唐了！
It's the final straw
这是越过底线的最后一根稻草！
This is lunacy Well, you know my views
真是神经病！你知道我的看法…
Utter lunacy
神经病！
But we daren't refuse
但我们不敢拒绝…
Not another chandelier
以免再发生那次的吊灯事件
Look, my friend, what we have here
朋友，看这是什么
"Dear André,  Re my orchestrations We need another first bassoon
亲爱的安德烈，跟我的乐队说下   我们需要另一个首席巴松演奏
"Every note's overblown  And that third trombone has to go
他每个音都用力过头了，第三长号也得换
"The man could not be deafer
我要的不是个聋子
"So please preferably  one who plays in tune"
请找个着调的
"Dear Firmin,  Vis-à-vis my opera  Some chorus members must be sacked
尊敬的弗明阁下，有些合唱团员   配不上我的歌剧，得把他们开除
"If you could find out which  has a sense of pitch
如果可以的话，请找些有乐感的
"Wisely though I've managed to assign a rather minor role To those who cannot act
我已经明智地给那些   演技差的安排了些配角的活
Outrage!
气死我了！
-  What is it now?  -  This whole affair
- 怎么了？   - 这简直要气死我！
Signora, please
夫人，请…
-  Now what's the matter?  -  Have you seen the size of my part?
现在又怎么了？
你看见我那个角色多小了吗？
-  Signora, listen  -
夫人，听我…
-  It's an insult  -  Not you as well
- 这太侮辱人了   - 你怎么也来了
-  Just look at this  - It's an insult
- 看看这些吧   - 太侮辱人了！
-  Please understand
请理解我们…
-  Signor, Signora
夫人！先生！
The things I have to do for my art
我得为了艺术这样去做
If you can call this gibberish "art"!
如果胡言乱语也能叫『艺术』的话！
Ah, here's our little flower
啊，这不是我们的小宝贝吗
Ah, Miss Daaé  Quite the lady of the hour
啊，大明星戴耶小姐来了
You have secured  the largest role in this Don Juan
你在『唐璜』里出演最重要的角色
Christine Daaé  She doesn't have the voice
克莉丝汀·戴耶？她没那嗓子
Signora, please
夫人，拜托
-Then I take it you're agreeing
这么说您也同意
She's behind this
是她捣的鬼
It appears we have no choice
看起来我们别无选择
She's the one behind this  Christine Daaé
克莉丝汀·戴耶，这都是她捣的鬼
How dare you?
你怎敢！
I'm not a fool
我又不傻！
You evil woman  How dare you?
你个邪恶的女人！你怎敢！
You think I'm blind?
你以为我瞎了？
This isn't my fault  I don't want any part in this plot
这不怪我！我不想掺和进这场阴谋
-  Miss Daaé, surely  -  But why not?
戴耶小姐，当然…
但为什么不呢？
PIANGI:  What does she say?
她说什么？
-  It's your decision  -  But why not?
- 都怪你的决定   - 但为什么不呢？
She's backing out
她走了
ANDRÉ:  You have a duty
你得负责任
I cannot sing it, duty or not
无论有没有责任，我都不会唱
Christine, Christine
克莉丝汀…克莉丝汀…
You don't have to  They can't make you
你不必…他们不能逼你…
Please, monsieur. Another note.
先生们，另一个便条
"Fondest greetings to you all
我善意的向各位致意
"A few instructions  just before rehearsal starts
排演开始前，我有几点指示
"Carlotta must be taught to act
卡洛塔得学习如何演戏
"Not her normal trick of..."  PHANTOM:  Not her normal trick of Strutting round the stage
不能像平常那样   傲慢地在舞台上踱步
Our Don Juan must lose some weight
我们的主角唐璜得减肥
It's not healthy in a man of Piangi's age
对皮安吉这年纪的男人来说肥胖不健康
And my managers must learn
我的经理们也得明白
That their place is in an office  Not the arts
他们擅长的是办公，不是艺术
As for Miss Christine Daaé
至于克莉丝汀·戴耶小姐
No doubt she'll do her best
无庸置疑，她一定会全力以赴
It's true her voice is good
她的歌喉也的确很好
She knows Though should she wish to excel
她也知道，若想更上层楼
She has much still to learn
还有很多需要学习的地方
If pride will let her return to me
她的上进心会使她回来找我
Her teacher, her teacher
她的老师，她的老师
Your obedient friend.
您的挚友…
"...and Angel"
和天使…
I can't. I won't do it.
不，我不能这样做
We have all been blind
我们都被蒙蔽了
And yet the answer is staring us in the face
答案就摆在我们眼前
This could be the chance To ensnare our clever friend
这是诱捕我们狡猾的朋友的绝佳机会
We're listening   Go on
- 我们听着呢   - 继续说
We shall play his game Perform his work
我们一起玩他的游戏   照他的要求演出他的戏剧
But remember we hold the ace
但我们手握王牌…
For if Miss Daaé sings He is certain to attend
如果戴耶小姐献唱，他一定会来观看
We make certain the doors are barred
确保大门紧锁
We make certain our men are there
通知警察前来
RAOUL:  We make certain they're armed
警察全副武装
The curtain falls His reign will end
演出落幕之时 便是他倒台之时
Madness!
疯狂！
-  I'm not so sure -  Not if it works
- 我不确定   - 这是不是可行
This is madness
太疯狂了！
The tide will turn
形势会逆转的！
Monsieur, believe me  There is no way of turning the tide
先生，相信我  你们无法改变现况
You stick to ballet
管好你的芭蕾舞吧！
Then help us
那就帮助我们
Monsieur, I can't
先生，我不能…
Instead of warning us
别站在那儿只会警告…
-  Help us!  - I wish I could
- 帮助我们   - 我希望我可以…
-   MANAGERS:  Don't make excuses
别找借口！
Or could it be that you're on his side?
还是你跟他就是一伙的？
She's his accomplice
她是他的帮凶
Monsieur, believe me, I intend no ill
先生，请相信我并无恶意
But, messieurs, be careful  We have seen him kill
但是各位先生，请小心…我们曾见过他杀人…
MANAGERS:  We'll say he'll fall  And fall he will
我们要他死他便不能活！
She's the one behind this  Christine
她就是幕后元凶！克莉丝汀！都是她干的！
-  This is the truth  -  This is all her doing
- 这是事实！克莉丝汀·戴耶！   - 这次是他的末日
音乐天使，感受我的愤怒
Hear his fury
听听我的警告！   感受他的愤怒！
（卡洛塔）她还想得到多高的荣誉？
很明显这个女人精神错乱
If you don't stop this, I'll go mad!
快停下来，我要疯了！
Raoul, I'm frightened  Don't make me do this
拉乌尔，我很怕   别逼我这么做
Raoul, it scares me  Don't put me through this ordeal by fire
拉乌尔，好可怕   别让我受此折磨
He'll take me, I know
他必定会带走我
We'll be parted forever
我们将永远分离
He won't let me go
他不会放我自由
What I once used to dream, I now dread
我旧日的梦想已成魔魇
If he finds me, it won't ever end
如果他找到我，我就再也回不来了
And he'll always be there
他永远会在那儿
Singing songs in my head
在我脑海中歌唱
He'll always be there
他永远会在那儿
Singing songs in my head
在我脑海中歌唱
She's mad.
她疯了
You said yourself
你曾说过
He was nothing but a man
他不过是个普通人
Yet while he lives
只要他还有一口气
He will haunt us till we're dead
就会至死纠缠我们
Twisted every way
一切都脱离掌控了
What answer can I give?
我还能有什么办法？
Am I to risk my life  to win the chance to live?
我非要冒生命危险才有一线生机吗？
Can I betray the man  who once inspired my voice?
怎能背叛曾为我的歌声插上翅膀的人？
Do I become his prey?
我已成他的猎物吗？
Do I have any choice?
我还有别的选择吗？
He kills without a thought
他杀戮毫不犹豫
He murders all that's good
他扼杀一切美好
I know I can't refuse
我知我不能拒绝
And yet I wish I could
但是却希望我能
Oh, God, if I agree
上帝啊，如果我这样做
What horrors wait for me?
将会遭遇怎样的恐怖？
In this, The Phantom's opera
在这魅影的歌剧院里
Christine, Christine
克莉丝汀，克莉丝汀
Don't think that I don't care
别以为我不在乎
But every hope and every prayer
丝丝希望，声声祈祷
Rests on you now
都依赖于你一人
I can't!
不行！
Christine!
克莉丝汀！
So, it is to be war between us!
那么，这就是我们之间的决战了！
But this time,
不过现在
my clever friend, the disaster will be yours!
我狡猾的朋友，你只有死路一条！
第四场 《唐璜的胜利》排演
ALL:  Hide your sword now, wounded knight
宝剑请入鞘，负伤之骑士
Your vainglorious gasconade Brought you to your final fight
自负的夸口为你带来最后的荣誉之战
For your pride, high price you've paid
为你的骄奢，你已付出高昂的代价
Silken couch and hay-filled barn  Both have been his battlefield
丝绸躺椅和干草谷仓，都曾是他的战场
(SINGING OFF-KEY)   Those who tangle with Don Juan
那些和唐胡纠缠的…
No, no, no! Chorus, rest, please.
不，不！合唱停一下
Don Juan: Signor Piangi. This is the phrase:
唐璜，皮安吉先生，应该是这样唱的
Those who tangle with Don Juan If you please.
『那些和唐璜纠缠的…』明白了吗？
(SINGING OFF-KEY)   Those who tangle with Don Juan
那些和唐璜纠残的…
Nearly, but no Those who tang! Tang! Tang!
好点了，不过还不行   『那些和唐璜纠缠，缠，缠…』
Those who tang! Tang! Tang!
『那些和唐璜纠缠，缠，缠…』
His way is better.  At least he makes it sound like music.
他唱的更好点，至少听起来有点乐感
Signora, would you speak that way  in the presence of the composer?
夫人，作曲家要是在这，您还这样说吗？
The composer is not here.
作曲家并不在这
- And if he were here, I would...  - Can you be certain of that,signora?
- 如果他在这，我会…   - 你就确定他不在这，夫人？
Once again, if you please, Signor Piangi.  After seven.
再来一次，皮安吉先生   七个节拍后开始
Five, six, seven...
五，六，七
(SINGING OFF-KEY)  Those who have been
那些和唐胡纠缠的…
tangling with Don Juan
哦，他还是不行…
What does it matter what notes we sing?
- 我不干了！我们唱得好或坏又怎样   - 耐心点，夫人
No one will know if it is right or wrong.
没人知道我们唱的怎么样
No one will care.
没人在意我们唱的怎么样
ALL:  Poor young maiden
可怜的少女
For the thrill on your tongue  of stolen sweets You will have to pay the bill
为舌尖上贪馋一点蜜糖，付出的代价是陪人上床
In sleep he sang to me
沉睡中他对我歌唱
In dreams he came
梦境中他近我身旁
That voice which calls to me
他的声音召唤着我
And speaks my name
喃喃轻诉我的名字
Little Lotte thought of  everything and nothing
小洛蒂心乱如麻
Her father promised her that  he would send her the Angel of Music
她父亲曾许诺,会派音乐天使来
Her father promised her
她父亲曾许诺…
第五场 墓园
You were once My one companion
你曾陪伴在我左右
You were all that mattered
你曾经是我的一切
You were once a friend and father
你曾待我亦父亦友
Then my world was shattered
我的世界稍纵粉碎
Wishing you were somehow here again
多么希望你能重现
Wishing you were somehow near
希望你仍未曾走远
Sometimes it seemed  If I just dreamed
错觉方才梦中相见
Somehow you would be here
仿佛约定此处再会
Wishing I could hear your voice again
渴望再次听你言语
Knowing that I never would
虽然明知已无可能
Dreaming of you won't help me to do
梦中之你无法助我
All that you dreamed I could
前去完成你的心愿
Passing bells and sculpted angels
冰冷寒风钟声逝
Cold and monumental
伫立不朽天使像
Seemed for you the wrong companions
它们不该是你的伴侣
You were warm and gentle
你是那么热情温柔
Too many years, fighting back tears
多年以来强忍泪水
Why can't the past just die?
为何往事无法消逝
戴  耶
1821-1872
Wishing you were somehow here again
希望你能此地重现
Knowing we must say goodbye
明知彼此天人永隔
Try to forgive, teach me to live
试着原谅教我生活
Give me the strength to try
给予我尝试的力量
No more memories
不再沉湎往昔回忆
No more silent tears
不再暗自潸然落泪
No more gazing across The wasted years
不再回顾过往云烟
Help me say Goodbye
给我勇气告别曾经
Help me say  Goodbye
Wandering child  So lost, so helpless
彷徨的孩子，失落无助
Yearning for my guidance
期盼我能给予指引
Angel or father  Friend or phantom
你是天使还是父亲
是我朋友抑或鬼魅
Who is it there, staring?
是谁在旁凝视着我？
（魅）你已忘记你的天使？   （克）我的天使请告诉我
是怎样的无尽渴望
Echo in this whisper
在细语中来回作响
Too long you've wandered in winter
（魅）风雪中已徘徊太久
Once again she is his
（拉乌尔）她再度被他夺走
Far from my fathering gaze
（魅）远离了我慈父般的呵护
Once again she returns
（拉乌尔）她再度回他身边
Wildly my mind beats against you
（克）虽然我心狂乱拒你
You resist yet your soul obeys
（魅）…你虽抗拒
- （克）但我的灵魂却顺从   - （魅）但你的灵魂却顺从
Into the arms of her...
（拉乌尔）再度回到…
-  Angel of Music, I denied you  -  Angel of Music, you denied me
- （克）音乐天使，我拒绝了你   - （魅）音乐天使，你拒绝了我
Angel or demo
是天使还是恶魔
-  Turning from true beauty  -  Turning from true beauty
（克和魅）背弃了真正的美
Luring her back from the grave
（拉）从墓园来，引诱她走
-  Angel of Music, my protector  -  Angel of Music, do not shun me
- （克）音乐天使，我的守护者   - （魅）音乐天使，不要逃避我
RAOUL:  Angel or dark seducer  Who are you strange angel?
（拉）天使还是恶魔
Come to me strange angel   Come to me strange angel
- （克）陌生天使来我身旁   - （魅）来到陌生天使身旁
I am your Angel of Music
我是你的音乐天使
Come to me, Angel of Music
来到音乐天使的身边
Angel of darkness, cease this torment!
黑暗天使！别再折磨她了！
I am your Angel of Music
（魅）我是你的音乐天使
Christine! Christine!
（拉）克莉丝汀！克莉丝汀！
Listen to me, whatever you may believe,  this man...
（拉）不管你信不信
This... This thing is not your father.
这人…这东西…不是你的父亲！
I am your Angel of Music
我是你的音乐天使
Let her go. For God's sake, let her go!
看在上帝的份上，放了她吧！放了她！
Come to me, Angel of Music
来到音乐天使的身边
- Christine!  - Raoul!
- 克莉丝汀！   - 拉乌尔
Bravo, monsieur, such spirited words.
好极了，先生！好一番豪言壮语
- More tricks, monsieur?  - Let's see, monsieur, how far you dare go.
- 还有什么花招，先生？   - 先生，让我看看您能走多远！
- More deception, more violence?  - That's right, that's right,
- 还要欺骗，还要强逼？   - 对呀，对呀
keep walking this way.
继续走下去啊
You can't win her love  by making her your prisoner.
把她囚禁也无法赢得她的真爱！
I'm here: I'm here, monsieur.  The angel of death.
我在这，先生，我是死亡天使
Come on. Come on. Don't stop. Don't stop.
跑啊，先生，别停下来！
So be it.
就这样吧！
Now, let it be war upon you both!
现在，我向你们宣战
第六场：『唐璜的胜利』首演之夜
You understand your instructions?
清楚你的任务了吗？
是的，长官
When you hear the whistle,  take up your positions.
听到哨声时，坚守你们的岗位
I shall then instruct you  to secure the doors.
我会安排你们看守大门
It is essential that  all doors are properly secured.
每个门都要好好看守
André, are we doing the right thing?
安德烈，你确定我们这样做没问题？
Well, have you got a better idea?
难道你还有更好的主意？
Monsieur Vicomte, am I to give the order?
子爵先生，可以下命令了吗？
Give the order.
下令吧
You, in the pit, do you have  a clear view of that box?
你，从乐池能看清包厢里吗？
Yes, sir.
可以的，长官
Remember, when the time comes, shoot.
记住，时机一到就射击
Only if you have to, but shoot to kill.
万不得已才开枪，但要一击致命
- How will I know, sir?  - You'll know.
怎么确定是否一击致命，长官？
到时候自然知道
Monsieur le Vicomte,  are you confident this will work?
子爵先生，你对此有信心吗？
- Will Miss Daaé sing?  - Don't worry, Firmin: André?
戴耶小姐会愿意演唱吗？
别担心，弗明，安德烈
We're in your hands, monsieur.
我们听从您的指令，先生
My men are now in position, sir.
我的人已经就位了，先生
Go ahead, then.
继续吧
(SHOUTING) Are the doors secure?
所有门都守好了吗？
- (DOORS CLOSING)  - MAN 1: Secure!
守好了
MAN 2: Secure!
MAN 3: Secure!
守好了
MAN 4: Secure!
MAN 5: Secure!
守好了
PHANTOM:  I'm here,  The Phantom of the Opera
歌剧魅影在此恭候
I'm here, The Phantom of the Opera
I'm here. I'm here. I'm here!
歌剧魅影在此恭候
Idiot! I said only when the time comes!
白痴！跟你说等待时机的！
- But, Monsieur le Vicomte.
但是子爵先生…
PHANTOM: No "buts"!
没什么『但是』！
For once, Monsieur Vicomte is right.
只有这次，子爵先生说的是对的…
Seal my fate tonight
我的命运将在今晚决定
I hate to have to cut the fun short  But the joke's wearing thin
可这笑话魅力已尽
Let my opera begin
让观众进场
让我的歌剧开始吧！
第七场 『唐璜的胜利』
ALL:  Here the sire may serve the dam
这里是先生伺候夫人的地方
Here the master takes his meat
这里是主人享受肉欲的地方
Here the sacrificial lamb Utters one despairing bleat
这里是小羊献身前，最后绝望哀嚎的地方
Poor young maiden
可怜的少女
For the thrill on your tongue  of stolen sweets You will have to pay the bill Tangled in the winding sheets
为舌尖上贪馋一点蜜糖，付出的代价是陪人上床
Serve the meal and serve the maid   Serve the meal and serve the maid
摆上酒宴，呈上少女，献给主人
Serve the master so that
当计划成功，酒宴摆好，少女献上时
When tables, plans and maids are laid  Don Juan triumphs  Once again
唐璜将又一次胜利
Passarino, faithful friend
（唐）帕萨里诺，我忠心的朋友
Once again recite the plan
将计划再说一次
Your young guest believes I'm you
（帕）你年轻的客人，会把我误认为你
I the master, you the man
我是主人，你是仆人
When you met, you wore my cloak
当你去见她时，穿我的斗篷
She could not have seen your face
她就看不到你的脸
She believes she dines with me
在她擅自借用的主人家中
In her master's borrowed place
她会以为是与我共进晚餐
Furtively we'll scoff and quaff
我们暗地偷笑，举杯庆祝
Stealing what in truth is mine
偷拿原本就属于我的物品
When it's late and modesty
当夜渐深
Starts to mellow with the wine
酒意渐渐软化她的羞怯
You come home  I use your voice
这时你回家，我借你的声音
Slam the door like crack of doom
就像噩运的叩门声
I will say, "Come hide with me
我就会说   『快，和我一起躲起来
"Where, oh, where? Of course, my room"
躲哪儿? 躲哪儿?   当然是我的房间啦』
Poor thing hasn't got a chance
可怜的人儿，连逃的机会都没
Here's my hat, my cloak and sword
这是我的帽子，斗篷和佩剑   胜利已在望
if I do not forget myself and laugh
但愿我不会忍不住忘形而笑
No thoughts within her head
她脑海里没有别的念头，只有欢乐
But dreams of love
她心中没有别的梦想，只有爱情
PASSARINO:  Master?
主人?
Passarino Go away,
帕萨里诺，走开！
for the trap is set And waits for its prey
陷阱已经设好，就等猎物上钩
You have come here  In pursuit of your deepest urge
你来这里，追逐你最深的渴望
In pursuit of that wish  Which till now has been silent, silent
你追逐的愿望至今仍是一片寂静…寂静
I have brought you That our passion may fuse and merge
我为你带来我们相溶相合的热情
In your mind  you've already succumbed to me Dropped all defenses  Completely succumbed to me
你的心已卸下防备向我屈膝臣服
Now you are here with me No second thoughts
如今你来到我身边，别无他想
You've decided Decided
你已作下决定…作下决定…
Past the point of no return
已然踏上不归路
No backward glances
无法再回眸
Our games of make believe  Are at an end
我们信任与虚妄的游戏已到尽头
Past all thought of "if" or "when" No use resisting
勿需更多思量，放弃无谓抵抗
Abandon thought And let the dream descend
放弃一切残念，让梦恣意沉淀
What raging fire shall flood the soul
怎样的烈火将吞噬灵魂？
What rich desire unlocks its door
多强的欲望打开了心门？
What sweet seduction lies before us
何等甜蜜的诱惑在面前？
Past the point of no return
踏上这条不归之路
The final threshold
穿越这最后的界限
What warm unspoken secrets Will we learn?
怎样温暖而无法言喻的秘密
Beyond the point  Of no return
等待着我们？在那不归路的尽头
You have brought me To that moment when words run dry
你带领我，来到言语失效的时刻
To that moment when speech Disappears into silence
此刻千言万语已化作沉默
Silence
沉默…
I have come here Hardly knowing the reason why
我来到这，却不知为何而来
In my mind  I've already imagined our bodies entwining
我心中已能想象我们身体
Defenseless and silent
沉默毫无防备地相互缠绕
And now I am here with you  No second thoughts
现在我和你一起，别无他想
I've decided  Decided
我已作下决定，作下决定…
Past the point of no return No going back now
踏上这条不归路，无法再回头
Our passion play has now At last begun
我们的激情游戏终于开始
Past all thought of right or wrong
抛下顾虑，不问对或是错
One final question
只剩最后一个疑问…
How long should we two wait Before we're one?
我们需多久才能结合为一
When will the blood begin to race? The sleeping bud burst into bloom?
何时能感到热血流淌，沉睡的花蕾蓦然绽放？
When will the flames at last Consume us?
何时火焰将我们焚烧殆尽？
BOTH:  Past the point of no return The final threshold
踏上这条不归路，穿越最后边界
The bridge is crossed So stand and watch it burn
界桥已越过，且回首看它焚毁
We've passed the point Of no return
我们已经踏上了这条不归之路
Say you'll share with me One love, one lifetime
说你将与我分享一生，唯一的爱
Lead me, save me From my solitude
将我从孤独的索居中引领拯救
Say you want me With you here Beside you
请说你要我在你身旁，伴你左右
Anywhere you go Let me go, too
无论你去何方我亦跟随你前往
Christine That's all I ask of...
克莉丝汀，这是我对你唯一的…
No!
不…不…
给我，先生！拿水来，先生
上楼，先生们，从这走！
Monsieur Vicomte, come with me!  I know where they are!
夏尼子爵，请跟我来！
我知道他们在哪
- Can I trust you?  - You must.
我能相信你吗？
But remember, keep your hand  at the level of your eyes.
你必须相信我   但千万记住…把手举至齐眼高
- But why?  - The Punjab lasso, monsieur.
- 为什么？   - 防着邦加绳索，先生
First Buquet, now Piangi.
先是布凯被吊住了，现在是皮安吉
Like this, monsieur. Look, I'II go with you.
就这样，先生，我跟你一块去
No, Meg! No: You stay here.
不，梅格！你留在这
Come with me, monsieur, do as I say.
跟我来，先生
But hurry, or we shall be too late.
按我说的做，快点，要不就迟了
第八场 地下迷宫
Down once more  To the dungeon of my black despair
重回我黑暗绝望的地牢
Down we plunge to the prison of my mind
一起坠入我心灵的牢笼
Down that path into darkness Deep as hell!
没入如同地狱般的黑暗
Why, you ask, was I bound and chained
你若问我为何自闭
In this cold and dismal place?
于这冰冷凄凉之处
Not for any mortal sin
不因我在人世间的罪
But the wickedness of my abhorrent face!
而是为这张丑陋的脸
CHORUS:  Track down this murderer He must be found
追捕杀人凶手 凶手必须被捕
Hounded out by everyone
人人得而诛之
Met with hatred everywhere
避之唯恐不及
No kind word from anyone No compassion anywhere
从未被同情，无人愿怜悯
Christine: (PANTING) Christine, why? Why?
克莉丝汀，克莉丝汀…   这是为什么？为什么？
Your hand at the level of your eyes At the level of your eyes
手举至眼齐高
CHORUS:  At the level of your eyes
举至眼齐高…
Level of your eyes
手举至眼齐高
He lives across the lake, monsieur.
他就住在湖的对面，先生
This is as far as I dare go.
我只敢到这么远
Madame Giry,thank you.
谢谢你，吉里夫人
CHORUS:  Track down this murderer  He must be found
追捕杀人凶手 凶手必须被捕
Track down this murderer  He must be found
Hunt down this animal who runs to ground
追捕这头野兽 堕入地穴的野兽
Too long he's preyed on us But now we know
他一直捕猎我们   但现在我们知道…
The Phantom of the Opera is here  Deep down below
歌剧魅影就在地下深处…
He's here, The Phantom of the Opera
歌剧魅影，他就在这
第九场 湖的彼岸
Have you gorged yourself at last  in your lust for blood?
你是否终于满足了你嗜血的欲望？
Am I now to be prey to your lust for flesh?
现在我是否已成为你肉欲的猎物？
That fate which condemns me  to wallow in blood
将我推进血海的悲惨命运
Has also denied me the joys of the flesh
也向我禁止了肉体的欢乐
This face The infection which poisons our love
这张残缺的脸，毒害了我们的爱
This face Which earned a mother's fear and loathing
这脸，让亲生母亲恐惧和厌恶
A mask, my first Unfeeling scrap of clothing
面具，是我第一件冰冷的衣物
Pity comes too late
怜悯来得太迟了
Turn around and face your fate
转过身面对你今后的命运
An eternity of this Before your eyes
注定你要永远面对这张脸
This haunted face Holds no horror for me now
如今我已不再 恐惧这张鬼魅似的脸
It's in your soul That the true distortion lies
扭曲的其实是你的灵魂
Wait: I think, my dear, we have a guest.
等等！亲爱的，我想我们有位客人
CHRISTINE: Raoul!
拉乌尔！
Sir, this is indeed an unparalleled delight.
这真令人无比的开心
I had rather hoped that you would come
我一直希望你能到来
No!
不！
And now, my wish comes true
现在我的愿望已实现
You have truly made my night
你的到来成就了今夜！
-  Free her!  Do what you will, only free her!
放了她！随你把我怎样，只要你放了她
Have you no pity?
难道你没有同情心？
Your lover makes a passionate plea
你情人的恳求还真申请
Please, Raoul, it's useless!
拉乌尔，这是没用的
I love her  Does that mean nothing?
我爱她！难道这毫无意义！
I love her Show some compassion!
我爱她！有点同情心吧！
The world showed no compassion to me!
这世界可没同情过我！
Christine, Christine
克莉丝汀…克莉丝汀…
Let me see her!
让我见她
Be my guest,
请便，先生
Monsieur, I bid you welcome
先生，欢迎您的到来
Did you think that I would harm her?
你认为我会伤害她吗？
Why should I make her pay  For the sins which are yours?
为何我会让她代你受过？
Order your fine horses now
召唤你的骏马吧！
Raise up your hand to the level of your eyes
把你的手举至眼齐高
Nothing can save you now
现在没人能救你了
Except perhaps Christine
或许除了克莉丝汀
Start a new life with me
和我开始新的生活
Buy his freedom with your love
用你的爱赎得他的自由
Refuse me and you send  your lover to his death
拒绝我就是让你的情人去死
This is the choice This is the point of no return!
这是你的选择，这里就是不归路
The tears I might have shed  For your dark fate
我本会为你黑暗的命运流的泪
And turn to tears of hate
已经冰冷，化作了对你的憎恨
Christine, forgive me  Please, forgive me
克莉丝汀，原谅我，请原谅我
I did it all for you and all for nothing
（拉）我为你付出一切却毫无回报
Farewell my fallen idol and false friend
（克）再见，堕落的偶像，虚伪的朋友
-  Too late for turning back  -  We had such hopes
- （魅）现在后悔已经太迟了   - （克）我曾有过幻想
-  Too late for prayers and useless pity  -  And now such hopes are shattered
- （魅）现在祈求和怜悯已经太迟了   - （克）只剩幻灭
-  Say you love him and my life is over  -  Past all hopes of cries for help
- （拉）说你爱他，我的人生也将结束   - （魅）无须抵抗
No point in fighting
（魅）无论你如何抉择，你都赢不了
-  Either way you choose he has to win  -  Either way you choose you cannot win
（拉）无论你如何抉择，他一定会赢
So, do you end your days with me
你只能与我白首偕老
Or do you send him to his grave?
或者你想送他去黄泉？
Why make her lie to you to save me?
何苦逼她为了救我而说谎！
-  Past the point of no return  -  Angel of Music
- （魅）你已置身不归路…   - （克）音乐天使
发发慈悲，克莉丝汀
- （拉）快说不！   - （克）为什么这样折磨我？   - （魅）穿越边界
（拉）别为了我牺牲你的生命
- （克）你什么时候才能明白   - （魅）他的命就是奖品，但是你必须去博
音乐天使
You deceived me  I gave my mind blindly
你欺骗了我，我盲目地对你付出真心
You try my patience.
你在考验我的耐心
Make your choice.
快做出抉择！
Pitiful creature of darkness
黑暗中可怜的造物
What kind of life have you known?
你究竟经历了怎样的人生？
God give me courage to show you
上帝给我勇气告诉你
You are not alone
你并不孤独
CHORUS:  Track down this murderer He must be found
追捕杀人凶手 凶手必须被捕
Take her, forget me, forget all of this!
带她走！忘了我，忘了这一切…
CHORUS:  Who is this monster?
那怪兽是谁！
猎杀这头野兽   躲入地下的野兽
Leave me alone! Forget all you've seen.
别管我…忘了见到的一切…
Go now, don't let them find you!
快点走…别让他们找到你们
CHORUS:  Revenge for Piangi  Revenge for Buquet
为皮安吉复仇！为布凯复仇！
Take the boat.
乘这艘船走，向我发誓…
Swear to me never to tell  of the secret you know...
不把这秘密告诉任何人
CHORUS:  This creature must never go free
他一直捕猎我们
The Phantom of the Opera
但现在我们知道   歌剧魅影就在地下深处
...of this Angel of Hell!
…地狱天使的秘密…
Go!Go now, and leave me!
走…快走，别管我！
Masquerade
化妆舞会
Paper faces on parade
假面舞者，盛装游行
Masquerade
化妆舞会
Hide your face  So the world Will never find you
遮住脸庞，世界便寻你不到
Christine  I love You
克莉丝汀，我爱你
Say you'll share with me One love, one lifetime
说你与我分享一生，唯一的爱
Say the word  And I will follow you
请你说出来，我将会跟随着你
Share each day with me Each night, each morning
与我分享每个黄昏，每个黎明
You alone can make  My song take flight
唯你能为我的歌声插上翅膀
It's over now
就这样结束了
The music Of the night
夜之乐章…
Daisy Maywood 饰 梅格·吉里
Sergei Polunin 饰 芭蕾舞者
Liz Robertson 饰 吉里夫人   2010 伦敦女王剧院版
Wendy Ferguson 饰 卡洛塔   2005-2008/2011 伦敦女王剧院版
Wynne Evans 饰 皮安吉
Barry James 饰 弗明先生   Gareth Snook 饰 安德烈先生   2008-2011 伦敦女王剧院版
Hadley Fraser 饰 拉乌尔
Sierra Boggess 饰 克莉丝汀   2006 拉斯维加斯版
Ramin Karimloo 饰 魅影   2003 伦敦女王剧院版 (饰拉乌尔)   2007 伦敦女王剧院版
Anthony Inglis 指挥   伦敦女王剧院版(音乐顾问)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING MASQUERADE)
安德鲁·劳埃德·韦伯 编剧/作曲
ANDREW LLOYD WEBBER: Thank you.
谢谢
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
谢谢，谢谢大家
Gosh, uh, do sit down, for goodness' sake.  I might talk for too long.
天啊，请大家坐下
我不会太罗嗦的
Gosh, when I was a little boy and I was first brought here by my mother
天啊，当我还是一个5岁的小孩的时候
when I was five, I think,  to a Promenade concert,
我母亲第一次带我来这
当时是个逍遥音乐会   注：参加音乐节的观众要一直站着观看演出 但可以随意走动，尤似散步
I think I heard Beethoven's Third Symphony,
我想那应该是贝多芬第三交响曲
and I don't think I could have ever,  ever believed,
我简直无法想象，有一天
sitting somewhere up there,
我能坐在那
that anything like this  would ever happen to my music.
无法想象我的音乐会在这里上演
And I have to thank, immediately,  Cameron Mackintosh.
我最应该感谢卡梅伦·麦金托什
What an extraordinary production  he's put together.
把本剧制作的如此出众
Thank you, Cameron.  We'll meet him in a moment.
谢谢你，卡梅伦，他随后会来与我们见面
But before I go any further,
在我继续这个话题之前
the wonderful thing about musicals is that
音乐剧的妙处在于
something has to happen  that brings them all together.
需要种因素，把其中各个元素组合起来
I mean, you can have a really great musical  and one aspect of it could be wrong,whether it be the production,
也许一部很优秀的音乐剧，其中某个环节出了差错
whether it be something to do with  how it's staged or anything,
也许是制作，舞台效果或别的什么
and it might get buried  and then take years to find again.
都可能让它被尘埃掩埋，数年后才能重见天日
But what happened so extraordinarily  with this is that everything came together with Cameron as the producer.
但我们的制作人，卡梅伦   就是可以将一切完美因素组合成一体的人
Before we go any further,
另外
I have to say that it would have never happened  without Maria Björnson,
我想说，如果没有玛丽亚·比昂松（舞美设计师）   就不会有今天的《歌剧魅影》
and of course...
当然
Maria Björnson
玛丽亚·比昂松
was, as all of you know,  the incredible designer of the show:
大家都知道，是这部戏无与伦比的舞台及服装设计
It was her vision combined, I think,  with everything else
是她的视野和其他诸多因素结合
that really brought us along.
带给我们这场美的享受
She tragically died some years ago.
很不幸，她在几年前去世
One of the greatest sadnesses  is that she's not here tonight,
今夜最大的遗憾就是她无法到场
but I hope we've honoured her spirit  in every way.
但是我希望我们能将她的精神传承下去
So. Maria, thank you.
玛丽亚，谢谢你
And I ought to say,  tonight's rather extraordinary
当然，今夜《歌剧魅影》的成功
because I know that there are  many companies of The Phantom of the Opera
也要感谢世界各地
watching this performance around the world because it's being beamed  around the world tonight.
同样在观看演出的这部戏的许多剧组，今晚盛况将会直播到全世界
And none, I suppose, more important
我想，没有谁
than the director who made it possible,
会比导演对此的贡献更大
who's in New York at the moment  with the New York Broadway company,
他现在身在纽约百老汇的剧组——哈尔·普林斯
Hal Prince So, hello, Hal!
你好，哈尔！
And thank you for everything, Hal.
谢谢你所做的一切，哈尔
So without any more ado, let's bring on  the original creative team from London.
所以接下来，请允许我介绍伦敦首演创作组
Here they come,  led by Sir Cameron Mackintosh.
他们来了，首先是卡梅伦·麦金托什爵士
Charles Hart, our lyricist, of course.
我们的词作者，查尔斯·哈特   灯光师，安迪·布里奇
Andy Bridge, our lighting, and above all  Gillian Lynne, who staged tonight.
尤其是今晚的舞台效果，吉莉安·林恩
Thank you, Gillian.
谢谢你，吉莉安
And the creative team  from the Albert Hall tonight.
还有来自阿尔伯特音乐厅的创意团队
Here they all are.
他们来了
Laurence, the director, in the middle.
中间是导演，劳伦斯
Now...Next, I have to thank our fantastic company.  What a fantastic show.
之后我想要感谢我们梦幻般的团队   为我们奉上今天这场梦幻的演出
Ramin, Sierra, you couldn't have  done me more proud.
拉明（魅影），希尔拉（克莉斯汀），你们让我无比骄傲
And Anthony Inglis  and the fantastic orchestra.
还有安东尼·易嘉士和他非凡的乐队
Just before we move on,
除此之外
I'm going to introduce you in a second  to the original London company,
我还想向大家介绍一下   伦敦首演时的团队
but I just would like you  to remember John Aron,Steve Barton, who of course played Raoul,  and Mary Millar,
希望大家能记得约翰·阿隆（皮安吉）和拉乌尔的扮演者斯提夫·巴顿
who sadly are no longer with us,
还有玛丽·米勒（吉里夫人），很不幸他们已不在人世
but they  were wonderful members of our original team.
但他们依然是我们伦敦首演团队的非凡成员
So, a small appreciation to them, please.
再次感谢他们
And here is our original London company.
我们有请伦敦首演团队
We have one other member  of the company tonight
还有一位伦敦首演团队成员…
who has hotfooted it  from the London Palladium,Michael Crawford
伦敦帕拉丁剧院火速赶来的麦克·克劳福德
Micheal Crawford 饰 魅影   1986 伦敦首演版   1988 百老汇首演版   1989 洛杉矶版
Finally.And I suppose this is very special for me.
最后介绍的这位对我来说非常特别
It is a great joy for me to welcome tonight my Angel of Music, Sarah Brightman.
我十分高兴能够欢迎   我的音乐天使——莎拉·布莱曼
Sarah Brightman 饰 克莉丝汀   1985 试演版   1986 伦敦首演版   1988 百老汇首演版
Without these two, we would not be here.
没有他们两人我们不会取得今日的成绩
Uh, we have one slight additional surprise.
我们还有一个小小的惊喜
Sarah has agreed to sing.
莎拉同意为大家献唱一曲
So, I'm going to leave you
那么，我现在就把你们交给
in the hands of the Angel of Music.
音乐天使
Maestro, take it away.
大师，开始吧
In sleep he sang to me
♪ 沉睡中他对我歌唱
In dreams he came
♪ 梦境中他近我身旁
That voice which calls to me
♪ 他的声音召唤着我
And speaks my name
♪ 喃喃轻诉我的名字
And do I dream again
♪ 我是否又重回梦境
For now I find
♪ 此时此刻我才发现
The Phantom of the Opera is there
♪ 歌剧魅影就在这里
Inside my mind
♪ 潜伏在我心灵深处
Sing once again with me
♪ 再次与我一起
Colm Wilkinson 饰 魅影
1985 试演版 1989 多伦多首演版
Our strange duet
♪ 同唱这奇妙的旋律
My power over you
♪ 我笼罩着你的力量
Anthony Warlow 饰 魅影
1990 澳大利亚首演版
2007-2009 澳大利亚/新西兰巡演版
Grows stronger yet
♪ 变得日益强大
And though you turn from me
♪ 尽管你欲转身而去
Peter Joback 饰 魅影
2012 伦敦版(计划中)
To glance behind
♪ 禁不住要回眸一瞥
The Phantom of the Opera is there
♪ 歌剧魅影就在这里
John Owen-Jones 饰 魅影
2001-2005 伦敦女王剧院版
2010-2011 伦敦女王剧院版
Inside your mind
♪ 潜伏在你心灵深处
Those who have seen your face
♪ 见过你真面目的人
Draw back in fear
♪ 他们在恐惧中却步
I am the mask you wear
♪ 我是你所戴的面具
It's me they hear
♪ 人们听到其实是我
My spirit and your voice
♪ 我的灵魂你的声音
In one combined
♪ 紧紧结合成为一体
The Phantom of the Opera is there
♪ 歌剧魅影就在这里
He's there,  The Phantom of the Opera
♪ 他就是那歌剧魅影
Beware, The Phantom of the Opera
♪ 歌剧魅影就在这里
In all your fantasies
♪ 在你所有的幻想中
You always knew
♪ 你始终都心如明镜
That man and mystery
♪ 那个男人，那个魅影
Were both in you
♪ 其实同存于你心中
BOTH:  And in this labyrinth
♪ 在这重重迷宫之中
Where night is blind
♪ 如同夜色一般黑暗
The Phantom of the Opera is there
♪ 歌剧魅影就在这里
Inside my mind
♪ 潜伏在我心灵深处
Sing! Sing, my Angel of Music!
♪ 歌唱吧，我的音乐天使
He's there, The Phantom of the Opera
♪ 他在这里，剧院魅影
- Sing!  - (VOCALISING)
歌唱吧
Sing!
Sing for me!
为我歌唱吧
I have brought you
♪ 我们带领你登上
To the seat of sweet music's throne
♪ 甜美的音乐宝座
To this kingdom  where all must pay homage to music
♪ 在这国度，人人都必须臣服于音乐
Music
♪ 音乐...
We have come here
♪ 我们来到此地
For one purpose and one alone
♪ 只为一个目的
Since the moment you first heard us sing
♪ 自从你第一次听到我们的歌声
We have needed you with me to serve me
♪ 我们便知道我们需要你在身边
To sing for his music
♪ 为他效力，为他歌唱
his music
♪ 为了他的音乐...
Night-time sharpens Heightens each sensation
♪ 深夜感触愈加敏锐
Darkness stirs And wakes imagination
♪ 暗潮翻滚，想象活跃
Silently the senses Abandon their defenses
♪ 无声无息，释放感觉
Slowly, gently Night unfurls its splendour
♪ 徐徐，缓缓，夜之炫魅舒展
Grasp it, sense it Tremulous and tender
♪ 感受，品味，温柔暗夜轻颤
Turn your face away From the garish light of day
♪ 躲避白昼刺目光芒
Turn your thoughts away From cold, unfeeling light
♪ 思绪逃离冷漠日光
And listen to the music Of the night
♪ 侧耳聆听夜之乐章
Close your eyes and surrender To your darkest dreams
♪ 闭目臣服幽深梦境
Purge your thoughts Of the life you knew before
♪ 洗尽心中红尘往事
Close your eyes Let your spirit start to soar
♪ 闭目随心，自由翱翔
And you'll live As you've never lived before
♪ 过眼云烟，恍若隔世
Softly, deftly Music shall surround you
♪ 轻柔，灵巧，音乐给你安抚
Hear it, feel it Closing in around you
♪ 聆听，感受，任由自己沉醉
Open up your mind Let your fantasies unwind
♪ 敞开心扉，放纵幻想
In this darkness
♪ 置身如此无边阴闇
Which you know you cannot fight
♪ 勿需抗拒
The darkness of the music Of the night
♪ 夜之乐章
Let your mind start a journey  through a strange new world
♪ 让心灵起航崭新旅程
Leave all thoughts of the world  you knew before
♪ 将前尘旧事抛诸身后
Let your soul Take you where you long to be
♪ 跟从灵魂，最深处的渴望
Only then Can you belong  To me
♪ 只有那时，你才心属于我
Floating, falling Sweet intoxication
♪ 飘荡，沉浮，迷醉不知归路
Touch me, trust me Savour each sensation
♪ 靠近，信任，感触逐一细品
Let the dream begin
♪ 让梦境开场，任暗夜笼罩
Let your darker side give in To the power of the music That I write
♪ 臣服于我谱写之乐章
The power of the music Of the night
♪ 魔力无穷的夜之乐章
You alone can make My song take flight
♪ 唯你能给它插上翅膀
Help me make the music Of the Night
♪ 助我共谱这夜之乐章
谢谢观赏TLF字幕   TLF字幕组欢迎你:sub.eastgame.org